[ translation & synchronization: 639 ]
[ 翻g 同步：639 ]
他神志不清，但一直在叫你名字。
快拿上怼
他身上只е@，
有@。
Are you here to kill me?
你是磉@⑽业幔
I know what this is.
我知道@是什N。
I've seen one before.
Many, many years ago.
我以前也^一，
很多、很多年以前。
It belonged to a man I met
in a half-remembered dream.
它凫兑我在粞Y遇的人，
一依稀得的粞Y，
A man possessed
of some radical notions.
他σ恍┋狂的念^著了魔。
What is the most resilient parasite?
什N是最有g诺募纳物？
A bacteria? A virus?
菌？病毒？
An intestinal worm?
c道寄生x？
Uh...
呃…
What Mr. Cobb is trying to say
考博先生想f的是……
An idea.
是意念，
Resilient. Highly contagious.
非常有g拧O具魅拘浴
Once an idea has taken hold of the brain,
一旦某意念了^X，
it's almost impossible to eradicate.
那就缀醪豢赡茉⑺根除，
An idea that is fully formed,
fully understood, that sticks.
一完整成形、被氐桌斫獾
意念牢牢地…
Right in there somewhere.
…附著在@骸
For someone like you to steal?
好你@拥娜巳ケI取？
Yes. In the dream state,
your conscious defenses are lowered...
是的。在舻BY，
你的有意R的防R就降低，
...and that makes your thoughts
vulnerable to theft.
以致於你的思想p而易e地被I取。
It's called extraction.
@就是所^的“提取”。
Mr. Saito, we can train
your subconscious to defend itself...
S藤先生，我能
你的意R矸蓝R自己，
...from even the most skilled extractor.
即便是於最熟的提取者。
How can you do that?
你如何能做到？
Because I am the most skilled extractor.
因槲揖褪亲钍炀的提取者。
I know how to search your mind
and find your secrets.
我知道如何搜索你的^X
K找出你的秘密，
I know the tricks.
我知道[T。
And I can teach them to you,
so that even when you're asleep...
我可以教你@些[T，
那拥脑即使你在睡粞Y，
...your defense is never down.
你的防R也^不降低。
Look, if you want my help, you're gonna
have to be completely open with me.
你看，如果你需要我的椭，
你必ξ彝耆地_\压：
I need to know my way around
your thoughts better than your wife...
我需要熟知你的思想，
比你的妻子、
...better than your therapist,
better than anyone.
比你的私人t生、
比任何人都更t解你。
If this is a dream,
and you have a safe full of secrets...
假O@是在你的粞Y，
你有一藏MC密的保U，
...I need to know what's in that safe.
我需要知道那保UY有什N。
In order for this all to work,
you need to completely let me in.
榱巳〉米詈玫男Ч，
你必完全把我自己人。
Enjoy your evening, gentlemen,
as I consider your proposal.
好好享受你的夜晚，先生，
我考]你的建h的。
He knows.
他知道了。
What's going on up there?
上面出什N事了？
Saito knows. He's playing with us.
S藤R破我了，他在耍我玩呢。
Doesn't matter. I can get it here.
Trust me.
o所^了。我可以在@Y拿到，
相信我。
The information is in the safe.
信息就在保UY。
He looked right at it
when I mentioned secrets.
才我一提到秘密，
他就往那望了一下。
What's she doing here?
她磉@致铮
Just head back to the room.
All right? I'll take care of this.
你先回房g，行幔
我硖理@。
Okay, make sure you do.
We're here to work.
好吧，想好了再做。
e忘了我有活阂帧
If I jumped, would I survive?
要是我跳下去，有可能活幔
With a clean dive, perhaps.
直接入海的，也S有可能。
Mal, what are you doing here?
，你磉@致铮
I thought you might be missing me.
我想也S你想我了。
You know that I am.
你知道我想你，
But I can't trust you anymore.
但我…我不再相信你了。
So what?
那又如何？
Looks like Arthur's taste.
看上去像是瑟的品味。
Actually, the subject is partial
to postwar British painters.
H上，主人偏鄱疳岬英家。
Please, have a seat.
吧，坐下吧。
Tell me...
告V我，
...do the children miss me?
孩子想我幔
You can't imagine.
你o法想像。
What are you doing?
你想质颤N？
Just getting some fresh air.
透c新r空狻
Stay where you are, Mal.
呆在那e樱。
Goddamn it.
的鬼！
Turn around.
D^身怼
The gun, Dom.
放下，多姆。
Please.
放下。
Now the envelope, Mr. Cobb.
有信封，考博先生。
Did she tell you?
Or have you known all along?
是她告V你的？
是你一直就知道？
That you're here to steal from me,
or that we are actually asleep?
知道你是磉@Y偷我的|西？
是知道我H上都是在粞Y？
I want to know the name of your employer.
我想知道你雇主的名字。
Ah, there's no use threatening him
in a dream, right, Mal?
啊，在粞Y威{他]什N用，
不是幔？
That depends on what you're threatening.
那要看你威{什N了。
Killing him would just wake him up.
⑺浪只使他K醒，
But pain...
但是疼痛…
Pain is in the mind.
疼痛在^XYa生。
And judging by the decor,
we're in your mind, aren't we, Arthur?
难b砼啵我@是
在你的^XY，不是幔瑟？
- What are you doing? It's too soon.
- But the dream's collapsing.
- 你怎N回事？提前就醒砹耍
- 我知道，但糸_始崩⒘恕
I'm gonna try to keep Saito under
a little bit longer.
得S藤在下面再逗留一crg，
We're almost there.
我快得手了。
He was close. Very close.
他差一c就得手了，差一cc。
Stop him!
抓住他！
（“C密”）
This isn't gonna work. Wake him up.
我想可能不行了，把他弄醒。
He won't wake.
他醒不^恚
- Give him the kick.
- What?
- o他反_/一踢。
- 什N？
Dunk him.
沉水Y。
He's out.
他醒了。
You came prepared, hmm?
你是有涠恚嗯？
Not even my head of security knows
this apartment. How did you find it?
就B我安全的人都不知道
@所公寓，你是怎NlF的？
It's difficult for a man of your position
to keep a love nest like this secret...
像你@游桓嘀氐娜宋铮要保守
@右鄢驳拿孛埽是相困y的，
...particularly where there's
a married woman involved.
特e是c一位已婚女人有涉r。
- She would never...
- Yet here we are.
- 她不露……
- 不^，我是砹耍
- With a dilemma.
- They're getting closer.
- 陷入了呻y。
- 他越碓浇了。
- You got what you came for.
- Well, that's not true.
- 你得到了想要的|西。
- 唔，你f得不Γ
You left out a key piece
of information, didn't you?
你T抹掉了PI的Y，是不是？
You held something back
because you knew what we were up to.
你保留了一些|西，
因槟阒道我的目的。
- Question is, why'd you let us in at all?
- An audition.
- }是槭颤N你我⑴cM怼
- 榱y。
- An audition for what?
- Doesn't matter. You failed.
- 槭颤Ny？
- o所^了，你失×恕
We extracted every bit of information
you had in there.
我已提取出了
你在那旱拿恳稽cY。
But your deception was obvious.
但是你的太@而易了。
- So leave me and go.
- You don't seem to understand, Mr. Saito.
- 所以，e┪亿so走吧。
- 你好像不太明白，S藤先生，
That corporation that hired us,
they won't accept failure.
雇蛭的公司，
他可不接受@拥氖。
We won't last two days.
我尾贿^商臁
Cobb?
考博？
Looks like I'm gonna have to do this
a little more simply.
看砦也坏貌裼
更吸c的k法碜隽恕
Tell us what you know!
Tell us what you know, now!
告V我你知道什N！
告V我你知道什N，快！
I've always hated this carpet.
我一直很@K地毯，
It's stained and frayed
in such distinctive ways.
它v不拉\、破破，很有特c，
But very definitely made of wool.
但^κK羊毛地毯。
Right now...
F在，
...I'm lying on polyester.
我s是躺在聚脂wS上。
Which means I'm not lying
on my carpet, in my apartment.
@就是f，我F在不是躺在
我公寓Y的地毯上。
You have lived up to your
reputation, Mr. Cobb.
你果然名不髂模考博先生。
I'm still dreaming.
我依然是在做簟
- How'd it go?
- Not good.
- M行得怎樱
- 不怎N印
Dream within a dream, huh?
I'm impressed.
做糁兄簦哈？
值貌诲e。
But in my dream, you play by my rules.
不^在我的粞Y，得按我的t硗妗
Ah, yes, but you see, Mr. Saito...
啊，好的，但是S藤先生，你知道……
We're not in your dream.
我不是在你的粞Y。
We're in mine.
我在我的粞Y。
Asshole. How do you mess up the carpet?
混蛋！你怎N把地毯搞砸了？
- It wasn't my fault.
- You're the architect.
- 不能算我的e。
- 你是O啊！
I didn't know
he was gonna rub his cheek on it!
我怎N知道他他的
把N在那上面！
That's enough.
e吵了。
You. What the hell was all that?
有你，@都是怎N回事？
- I have it under control.
- I'd hate to see you out of control.
- 我有k法掌控。
- 我倒是X得你快失控了。
We don't have time for this.
I'm getting off at Kyoto.
我]rg再做了。
我要在京都下。
He's not gonna check every compartment.
槭颤N？他不z查每的。
Yeah, well, I don't like trains.
好吧，我不喜g火。
Listen. Every man for himself.
著，我各自奔命吧。
Yes, hello?
喂，你好？
- Hi, Daddy. - Hi, Dad.
- 嗨，爹地。 - 嗨，爹地。
Hey, guys. Hey. How are you?
How you doing, huh?
嘿，小砘，嘿，你好幔
你怎N影。嗯？
- Good. -Okay, I guess.
- 好的。- 我想行。
Okay? Who's just okay?
Is that you, James?
行？是lf行的？
是你幔詹姆士？
Yeah. When are you coming home, Dad?
是的。你什Nr候回家啊，爹地？
Well, I can't, sweetheart. I can't.
Not for a while, remember?
噢，我不能，海我不能。
r回不了，得幔
Why?
槭颤N？
Look, I told you, I'm away
because I'm working, right?
你看，我告V^你，我…我不在家
因槲乙工作，幔
Grandma says you're never coming back.
外婆f你再也不回砹恕
Phillipa, is that you?
菲利帕，那是你幔
Put Grandma on the phone for me, will you?
外婆砺，行幔
She's shaking her head.
她在u^。
Well, just hope she's wrong about that.
好吧，希望她f得不Α
Daddy?
爹地？
Yeah, James?
什N，詹姆士？
Is Mommy with you?
咪和你在一起幔
James, we talked about this.
詹姆士，我^@了，
Mommy's not here anymore.
咪再也不在@Y了。
Where?
那在哪海
That's enough, kids. Say bye-bye.
行了，孩子，f掰掰。
Listen, I'm gonna send some presents
with Grandpa, all right?
著，我…我外公
ФY物o你，知道幔
And you be good, you be...
你要乖啊，你要……
- Our ride's on the roof.
- Right.
- 我的\工具在琼了。
- 知道了。
Hey, are you okay?
嘿，你]事吧？
Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine. Why?
]事，我很好。怎N？
Well, down in the dream,
Mal showing up.
在下面粞Y的r候，
又出F了。
Look, I'm, uh, sorry about your leg.
Won't happen again.
你看，我…呃，很抱歉你的腿，
不再有@拥氖铝恕
It's getting worse, isn't it?
情r得越碓皆懔耍是幔
One apology's all you're getting, all right?
你想要什N拥牡狼改兀瑟？
- Where's Nash?
- He hasn't shown. You wanna wait?
- {什在哪海
- ]到他，想等等幔
We were supposed to deliver
Saito's expansion plans...
尚r之前我就把
S藤的U展…
...to Cobol Engineering two hours ago.
…交o“科博工程公司”了。
By now, they know we failed.
It's time we disappear.
F在他已知道我失×耍
我是R上消失的好。
- Where you gonna go?
- Buenos Aires.
- 你要去哪里？
- 布宜Z勒斯。
I can lie low there, maybe sniff out
a job when things quiet down. You?
我可以在那罕鼙茱L^，等事情平息下磲幔
也S再瞅瞅有什N活嚎帧Ｄ隳兀
Stateside.
回美。
Send my regards.
代我好。
He sold you out. Thought to come
to me and bargain for his life.
他你露了W，想起碚椅遥
想和我商量保他的命。
So I offer you the satisfaction.
所以我可以你得到M足。
It's not the way I deal with things.
@不是我行事的方式。
- What will you do with him?
- Nothing.
- 你拿他怎N樱
- 不怎N印
But I can't speak for Cobol Engineering.
但我不能代表“科博工程公司”。
- What do you want from us?
- Inception.
- 你究竟想奈@旱玫绞颤N？
- “l”。
- Is it possible?
- Of course not.
- 有可能幔
- 然不可能。
If you can steal an idea
from someone's mind...
既然你能e人的^XYI取意念，
...why can't you plant one
there instead?
槭颤N不能相地
在那褐踩肽意念呢？
Okay, here's me planting
an idea in your head.
好吧，F在我要在你^XY
植入一意念：
I say, "Don't think about elephants".
What are you thinking about?
我δ阏f：“e去想大象。”
你F在在想什N？
Elephants.
大象。
Right. But it's not your idea,
because you know I gave it to you.
]e，但@K不是你自己的意念，
因槟阒道@是我o你的。
The subject's mind can always
trace the genesis of the idea.
主w的^X能
追到那意念的源^，
- True inspiration's impossible to fake.
- That's not true.
- 真正的`感是不可能卧斓摹
- 你f得不Α
- Can you do it?
- Are you offering me a choice?
- 你能做？
- 你@是在我做x幔
Because I can find my own way
to square things with Cobol.
我可以自己想k法[平
c“科博公司”的^。
Then you do have a choice.
那你就自己x窈昧恕
Then I choose to leave, sir.
那我就x耠x_，先生。
Tell the crew where you want to go.
告VCM你要去哪骸
Hey, Mr. Cobb.
嘿，考博先生！
How would you like to go home?
你想不想回家啊？
To America. To your children.
回美，回到你孩子身？
You can't fix that. No one can.
@你k不到吧，]人能k到。
- Just like inception.
- Cobb, come on.
- 就像“l”？
- 考博，走吧。
- How complex is the idea?
- Simple enough.
- 那意念有多}s？
- 足蚝巍
No idea is simple when you need
to plant it in somebody else's mind.
]有“蔚囊饽睢币徽f，
如果你想把它植入到e人的^XY。
My main competitor is
an old man in poor health.
我的主要κ质且老人，
F在健康夯，
His son will soon inherit control
of the corporation.
他的鹤硬痪⒗^承掌握他的企I。
I need him to decide to break up
his father's empire.
我需要他做出Q定，
拆分他父H的aI帝。
- Cobb, we should walk away from this.
- Hold on.
- 考博，我躲著c@拥氖隆
- 等等。
If I were to do this,
if I even could do it...
如果我意做@事，
如果…如果我真的能蜃龅剑
...I'd need a guarantee.
我需要你也能保C。
- How do I know you can deliver?
- You don't.
- 我怎N知道你能做到？
- 你是不知道，
But I can.
但是我能。
So do you want to take
a leap of faith...
怎Nf，你是希望硪
信心上的wS呢？
...or become an old man,
filled with regret...
是想以後等你老了，
心中充Mz憾，
...waiting to die alone?
在孤中等待死亡？
Assemble your team, Mr. Cobb.
And choose your people more wisely.
召集你的人R吧，考博先生，
@次你x人的r候要更明智一些。
Look, I know how much you wanna go home.
著，我知道你非常希望回家，
This can't be done.
但@事我植涣恕
Yes, it can.
Just have to go deep enough.
不，可以郑
只要你能走得足蛏睿
You don't know that.
你根本不知道。
I've done it before.
我以前做^。
Who'd you do it to?
φl做的？
Why are we going to Paris?
我槭颤N去巴黎？
We're gonna need a new architect.
我需要新O。
You never did like your office, did you?
你真的是很不喜g你的k公室，是幔
No space to think in that broom cupboard.
在那拥咧Y]有空g思考。
Is it safe for you to be here?
你磉@喊踩幔
Extradition between France
and the United States...
法和美之g的引渡手m…
...is a bureaucratic nightmare,
you know that.
…是噩舭愕姆蔽目d，@你知道。
【e去瑞士：）】
I think they might find a way
to make it work in your case.
我想於你的案子
也S他改作L。
Look, I, uh, brought these for you to...
你看，我，呃…I了@些想你…
...give to the kids
when you have a chance.
…有C的Ыo孩子。
It'll take more than
the occasional stuffed animal...
光靠偶送些毛q玩具，
...to convince those children
they still have a father.
你不能孩子相信
他有你@父H。
I'm just doing what I know.
I'm doing what you taught me.
我只是在做我熟悉的事情，
而且我做的正是你教我的。
I never taught you to be a thief.
我]教^你去做小偷。
No, you taught me to navigate
people's minds.
是的，但你教^我如何
{S人的^X。
But after what happened...
但是自某隽四羌事之後，
...there weren't a whole lot
of legitimate ways...
我已]k法再以
完全合法的方式…
...for me to use that skill.
…硎褂眠@N技能了。
What are you doing here, Dom?
你磉@Y究竟做什N，多姆？
I think I found a way home.
我想我找到了回家之路。
It's a job for some very,
very powerful people.
槟澄环浅！⒎浅Ｓ萘Φ娜宋
完成一工作，
People who I believe can fix
my charges permanently.
我相信那人可以一谟酪莸
解Qξ业闹缚兀
But I need your help.
但是我需要你的椭。
You're here to corrupt
one of my brightest and best.
你磉@Y是想
我最明和最好的W生。
You know what I'm offering.
Let them decide for themselves.
你知道我可以提供怎拥C，
你得他自己Q定。
- Money.
- Not just money.
- 殄X？
- 不只是X。
You remember.
得幔
It's the chance to build cathedrals,
entire cities...
l不想有C斫ㄔ齑蠼烫谩
整座整座的城市，
...things that never existed...
那些]存在^的|西、
...things that couldn't exist
in the real world.
那些在F世界中
不可能存在的|西？
So you want me to let someone else
follow you into your fantasy?
所以你…你希望我另一人
碜冯S你M入你的幻界？
They don't actually come
into the dream.
他不必真正M入到粞Y，
他只要…
They just design the levels
他只要O好每一拥艟常
and teach them to the dreamers.
That's all.
K教o主粽撸那泳托辛恕
Design it yourself.
你自己O呢？
Mal won't let me.
不允S我。
Come back to reality, Dom.
回到F戆桑多姆，
- Please.
- Reality.
- 行幔
- F？
Those kids, your grandchildren...
我的孩子、你的外O，
...they're waiting for their father
to come back home.
他正等著他的父H回家，
That's their reality.
@就是他的F。
And this job, this last job,
that's how I get there.
@工作、@最K的工作，
我如以。
I would not be standing here
if I knew any other way.
我不站在@Y的，
要是我知道有e的什Nk法。
I need an architect
who's as good as I was.
我需要O，
和我那耙影舻脑O。
I've got somebody better.
我有更好的人x。
Ariadne?
阿Y阿德涅？
I'd like you to meet Mr. Cobb.
我想你一下考博先生。
Pleased to meet you.
很高dJR你。
If you have a few moments,
如果你有crg，
Mr. Cobb has a job offer
he'd like to discuss with you.
考博先生有份工作提供，
他想和你。
A work placement?
工xn程之的？
Not exactly.
不完全是。
I have a test for you.
我想y你一下。
You're not gonna tell me
anything first?
你不想先透露我c
那是什N拥墓ぷ鳎
Before I describe the job,
I have to know you can do it.
在我描述@份工作之前，
我得先知道你必能偃巍
- Why?
- It's not, strictly speaking, legal.
- 槭颤N？
- 栏竦卣f它不太合法。
You have two minutes to design a maze
that it takes one minute to solve.
o你煞昼rgO出一
需要花一分解_的迷m。
Stop.
停。
Again.
再怼
Stop.
停。
You're gonna have to do better than that.
你得加把挪判邪
That's more like it.
@差不多。
They say we only use a fraction
of our brain's true potential.
一般J槲只是部分地利用了
我大X的真正的能，
Now, that's when we're awake.
然，那是指我醒著的r候；
When we're asleep,
our mind can do almost anything.
我在睡眠中，我的^X
缀蹩梢宰鋈魏问虑椤
Such as?
比如f？
Imagine you're designing a building.
You consciously create each aspect.
O想你正在O一座建B，
你有意R地造它的方方面面。
But sometimes, it feels like
it's almost creating itself,
但有的r候，你X得那些造
自然而然地就a生了，
if you know what I mean.
你明白我的意思幔
Yeah, like I'm discovering it.
是的，像是我o意撞的。
Genuine inspiration, right?
真正的`感，幔
Now, in a dream,
our mind continuously does this.
如果是在粞Y，我的^X
Bm不嗟刈鲋@拥氖拢
We create and perceive
our world simultaneously.
我一造，同r
一感知我的世界，
And our mind does this so well
that we don't even know it's happening.
我的^X做得如此出色，
以至於我甚至都不知道l生了什N。
That allows us to get right
in the middle of that process.
那使得我能
直接介入@一^程之中。
- How?
- By taking over the creating part.
- 怎N介入？
- 通^起造的角色。
Now, this is where I need you.
@Y就是我需要你的地方了：
You create the world of the dream.
你造出糁械氖澜纾
We bring the subject into that dream,
我把主w入那簦
and they fill it
with their subconscious.
然後他用自己的意R
充M那艟场
How could I ever acquire enough detail
to make them think that it's reality?
我怎N可能@得足虻募
好他J槟蔷褪钦娴模
Well, dreams, they feel real
while we're in them, right?
我做的簦感X都很真，
只要我是在粞Y，N？
It's only when we wake up that we
realize something was actually strange.
只有我醒了之後，
才意R到有些|西其很奇怪。
Let me ask you a question.
我你}：
You never really remember
the beginning of a dream, do you?
你…你砘不起
某舻拈_^，幔
You always wind up
right in the middle of what's going on.
你只得糇龅揭话耄
然後就嗔说哪且徊糠帧
I guess, yeah.
我想是的，是@印
So how did we end up here?
那N我怎N在@旱模
Well, we just came from the, uh...
唔，我是摹呃……
Think about it, Ariadne.
How did you get here?
仔想想，阿Y阿德涅，
你怎N磉@旱模
Where are you right now?
你F在究竟在哪海
We're dreaming?
我在做簦
You're in the middle
of the workshop, sleeping.
你H上F在正在
一g工S人X，
This is your first lesson
in shared dreaming. Stay calm.
@是你分享艟车牡谝徽n。
e慌。
If it's just a dream,
then why are you?
如果@只是一簦
那你槭颤N……？
Because it's never just a dream, is it?
因楦杏X完全不像是在做簦是不是？
And a face full of glass hurts like hell.
M的碎玻璃渣，疼得要命。
When you're in it, it feels real.
只要你在粞Y，感X就很真。
That's why the military
developed dream sharing.
@就是槭颤N方
研l出了艟撤窒硐到y，
It was a training program
for soldiers to shoot,
他有目，
士兵互相射簟
stab and strangle each other
and then wake up.
刺、和扼死，最後再醒^怼
How did architects become involved?
O在其中起什N作用？
Well, someone had to design
the dreams, right?
得有人碓O艟常N？
Why don't you give us
another five minutes?
你再o我五分w一下吧。
Five minutes?
五分？
What? We were talking
for, like, at least an hour.
怎N？我了
好像至少有一^。
In a dream, your mind
functions more quickly...
在粞Y你的^X\D得更加快，
...therefore time seems
to feel more slow.
因此rg似乎就感X慢了。
Five minutes in the real world
gives you an hour in the dream.
真世界的五分
o你一小r在粞Y。
Why don't you see what you
can get up to in five minutes?
槭颤N你不再五分，
看看你能做些什N？
You've got the basic layout.
Bookstore, cafe.
你有了@些基本的丫帧―
店、咖啡^，
Almost everything else is here too.
@Y似乎一切有M有。
- Who are the people?
- Projections of my subconscious.
- @些人物是l？
- 是我的意R的投影。
- Yours?
- Yes.
- 你的？
- 是的。
Remember, you are the dreamer.
You build this world.
你看，你是主粽撸
你建造@世界。
I am the subject. My mind populates it.
我是主w，我的精神充斥在@Y。
You can literally talk to my subconscious.
你其可以和我的意Rυ，
That's one of the ways we extract
information from the subject.
正因槿绱耍我可以
闹黧w那Y提取出Y。
How else do you do it?
能做些e的幔
By creating something secure,
like a bank vault or a jail.
通^造出一些安全的地方，
比如y行的金旎蚴潜Oz，
The mind automatically fills it with
information it's trying to protect.
^X就自拥
需要保o的Y放在Y面，
- You understand?
- Then you break in and steal it?
- 你明白幔
- 然後由你黻J入和I取？
Well...
@嘛……
I guess I thought that the dream space
would be all about the visual...
我想我之前以粞Y的空g
只和X形象有P，
...but it's more about the feel of it.
但F在看砀像和感X有P。
My question is what happens when you
start messing with the physics of it all?
我的}是，如果你想和
物理律_起玩笑l生什N？
It's something, isn't it?
延^吧，你f呢？
Yes, it is.
是啊。
Why are they all looking at me?
槭颤N他都那忧浦我？
Because my subconscious feels that
someone else is creating this world.
因槲业意R感X到了
有另外的人在造@世界。
The more you change things,
你改的事物越多，
the quicker the projections
start to converge on you.
@些投影就越快地
_始向你聚n^怼
Converge?
聚n？
They sense the foreign nature
of the dreamer.
他察X出主粽叩耐傩裕
They attack, like white blood cells
fighting an infection.
就像白胞那樱
向受到感染的部位l起攻簟
- What, they're gonna attack us?
- No, no.
- 怎N，他攻粑幔
- 不，不，
Just you.
只攻裟恪
This is great, but I'm telling you,
@雍馨簦不^我跟你f，
if you keep changing things like this...
如果你像@硬煌５馗淖事物……
Jeez, mind telling your subconscious
to take it easy?
天哪！能不能招呼下你的意R，
他放pc？
It's my subconscious.
Remember? I can't control it.
那是我的意R，
要知道，我是]k法控制的。
Very impressive.
相能帧
I know this bridge.
This place is real, isn't it?
我JR@座颍
@地方是真的，幔
Yeah, I cross it every day
to get to the college.
是啊，我每天去大W都要穿^。
Never re-create places from your memory.
千fe用你的碓造h境，
Always imagine new places.
是要想像出新的h境。
You draw from stuff you know, right?
可是你得用你熟悉的|西碓O吧？
Only use details. A streetlamp
or a phone booth. Never entire areas.
只能用的|西，比如呃…一K街簦
或一亭，^不能用整^域。
- Why not?
- Building a dream from your memory...
- 槭颤N不能？
- 因槿绻你用建造艟场
...is the easiest way to lose your grasp
on what's real and what is a dream.
使你很容易失去把握，
分不清什N是F，而什N又是簟
- Is that what happened to you?
- Listen to me.
- 你是不是就是@樱
- 你著，
This has nothing to do
with me, understand?
我不是在f我，你明白幔
That why you need me
to build your dreams?
@就是槭颤N你需要
我硖婺阍舻脑因？
Hey, get off of her. Back up. Back up.
嘿，放_她。往後退，後退！
- Cobb! Cobb!
- Get off of her!
- 考博！考博！
- 放_她！
- Let me go! Let me go!
- Mal!
- 放_我！放_我！
- ！
- Mal!
- Cobb! Wake me up!
- ！
- 考博！我醒恚
- Wake me up! Wake me up!
- No!
- 我醒恚∽我醒恚
- 不！
- Mal, no! No!
- Wake me up!
- ，不！不！
- 快弄醒我！
Hey, hey, hey. Look at me.
You're okay. You're okay.
嘿，嘿，嘿！看著我。
你]事吧？你]事吧？
- Hey.
- Why wouldn't I wake up?
- 嘿。
- 椤槭颤N我醒不^恚
There was still time on the clock.
r器上的rg]到，
You can't wake up from
within the dream unless you die.
你不可能粞Y面
自己醒恚除非你死掉。
- She'll need a totem.
- What?
- 她需要Dv。
- 什N？
A totem, it's a small personal...
Dv是一件小小的人……
That's some subconscious
you've got on you, Cobb!
你的那意R
可真害的啊，考博！
- She's a real charmer.
- Oh.
- 她是大美女啊！
- 噢…
- I see you met Mrs. Cobb.
- She's his wife?
- 我想你是遇考博太太了。
- 她是他妻子？
Yeah. So a totem. You need
a small object, potentially heavy.
是的。你看…Dv，你需要
一小物件，可能有c沉，
Something you can have on you
that no one else knows.
一件你能Srг谏砩系|西，
但是e人不知道。
- Like a coin?
- No.
- 比如f硬牛
- 不，
It needs to be more unique than that.
Like, this is a loaded die.
必比那更特才行。
比如，@是灌了U的骰子。
No, I can't let you touch it.
That would defeat the purpose.
不，我不能你碰它，
那Я怂的作用。
See, only I know
the balance and the weight...
瞧，只有我才t解@
特殊的灌U骰子的…
...of this particular loaded die.
…平衡和受力方式。
That way, when you look at your totem...
@右恚你^察你的Dvr，
...you know beyond a doubt that
you're not in someone else's dream.
你就能毫o疑地知道
你]有在e人的粞Y。
I don't know if you can't see
what's going on,
我…我不知道，你是看不到
那Yl生的事呢，
or if you just don't want to...
是你只是不意去看？
...but Cobb has some serious problems
that he's tried to bury down there.
考博有一些很乐氐}
他D埋藏在那下I，
And I'm not about to just open my mind
to someone like that.
我可]打算向像他那拥娜
敞_我的心扉。
She'll be back. I've never seen anyone
pick it up that quickly before.
她回淼模我以前]遇到^
什N人W得那N快的。
Reality's not gonna be enough for her
now, and when she comes back...
F⒉辉倌M足她了。
等她回怼
When she comes back,
you're gonna have her building mazes.
等她回磲幔
你要椭她建造迷m了。
- Where are you gonna be?
- I gotta go visit Eames.
- 你要去哪海
- 我得去找伊姆斯。
Eames? No, he's in Mombasa.
It's Cobol's back yard.
伊姆斯？不，他在蒙巴_【肯雅】，
那可是“科博”的自家後院啊。
It's a necessary risk.
不得不冒@U。
- Well, there's plenty of good thieves.
- We don't just need a thief.
- 可是好小偷多的是嘛。
- 我不止是需要小偷，
We need a forger.
我需要的是造假。
Rub them together all you want,
they're not gonna breed.
你再怎N使糯辏
也搓不出仔【指Ia】怼
You never know.
l知道呢。
I'm gonna get you a drink.
我o你弄杯喝的。
You're buying.
你碣I。
- Your spelling hasn't improved.
- Piss off.
- 你的拼]什NLM啊。
- L你的。
How's your handwriting?
你的法怎N恿耍
- It's versatile.
- Good.
- 各NPE。
- 很好。
Thank you very much.
非常感x。
Inception.
“l”。
Now, before you bother telling me
it's impossible, let me...
好吧，在你失去耐心告V我
@是不可能的之前，我……
No, it's perfectly possible.
It's just bloody difficult.
不，@完全有可能，
只是太他的困y而已。
Interesting. Because Arthur keeps
telling me it can't be done.
有意思，因瑟是f@做不成。
Hmm. Arthur. You still working
with that stick in the mud?
唔…瑟，你在和那
墨守成的木^共事？
He is good at what he does, right?
他有他的特L，不是幔
Oh, he's the best,
but he has no imagination.
噢，是很好，但他根本]想像力。
Not like you.
不像你。
Listen, if you're gonna perform inception,
you need imagination.
著，如果你想施“l”，
你需要想像力。
Let me ask you something.
Have you done it before?
我你，你以前做^幔
We tried it. Uh, we got the idea
in place, but it didn't take.
我^，呃，我已⒁饽
植入了^X，但是]有固住。
- You didn't plant it deep enough?
- No, it's not just about depth.
- 你是不是植入得不蛏睿
- 不，不只和深度有P，你知道…
You need the simplest version of the idea...
你需要⒁饽詈化到最蔚男问剑
...in order for it to grow naturally
in your subject's mind.
@硬拍苁顾在主w的^X中自然成L。
It's a very subtle art.
@是非常精妙的技。
So, what is this idea that you need to plant?
那N你需要植入的是怎拥囊饽钅兀
We need the heir of a major corporation
to dissolve his father's empire.
我需要一家大型企I的^承人
分解他父H的帝。
Right there you have
various political motivations...
你看，你可以母鞣N各拥
政治C的角度砜]，
...and anti-monopolistic sentiments
and so forth.
例如反嗟那榫w等等的，
But all of that stuff, it's, um...
T如此的玩意海PI是，呃…
It's really at the mercy of your
subject's prejudice, you see?
PIc在於你的那主w
有什N成，你明白幔
What you have to do is
start at the absolute basic.
你要做的就是淖罨本之c切入。
Which is what?
那是什N？
The relationship with the father.
c他父H的PS。
- Do you have a chemist?
- No, not yet.
- 你有了]？
- ]，]有。
Right. Okay, well,
there's a man here, Yusuf.
好吧，正好，@Y有人，尤素福，
He, uh, formulates his own versions
of the compounds.
他，呃…他用自己的配方合成。
Why don't you take me there?
你什Nr候我去他？
Once you've lost your tail.
The man at the bar.
等你甩掉你的尾巴之後。
注意吧台那人。
Cobol Engineering.
“科博工程公司”的。
That price on my head,
was that dead or alive?
我人^是什N_r碇？
是“o死活”幔
Don't remember.
Let's see if he starts shooting.
不得了，看看他
向不向你_好了。
Run interference.
你替我打岔，
I'll meet you downstairs in the bar in,
say, uh, half an hour?
我在@吧的窍屡c你合，
大s…半小r之後怎N樱
- Back here?
- This is the last place they'd suspect.
- 回到@Y？
- 他做粢膊想到。
All right.
好吧。
Freddy. Freddy Simmonds.
弗雷迪，弗雷迪・西蒙？
My God, it's you, isn't it?
天哪，真是你，幔
No, it isn't you.
不，不是的。
Not dreaming now, are you?
你F在]做舭桑在做幔
Get him!
抓住他！
There!
那海
One cafe.
噢，呃…咖啡，一…一杯咖啡。
Shh.
u……
One cafe.
一杯咖啡。
Care for a lift, Mr. Cobb?
想要搭幔考博先生？
- What are you doing in Mombasa?
- I'm here to protect my investment.
- 你蒙巴_质颤N？
- 我必保o我的投Y。
Ah. So this is your idea
of losing a tail, huh?
啊，你就是@硭ξ舶偷模嗯？
Different tail.
@l尾巴不同。
Cobb said you'd be back.
考博f你一定回怼
- I tried not to come, but...
- But there's nothing quite like it.
- 我著想不恚但是……
- 但是@一切的_非同こ！
It's just...
@只是…
...pure creation.
…粹的造。
Shall we take a look
at some paradoxical architecture?
我砜匆恍┿Ｕ式的建B吧。
You're gonna have to master a few tricks...
如果你要建造三油暾的艟常
...if you're gonna build three complete
dream levels. Excuse me.
你必掌握一些E[。Σ黄稹
What kind of tricks?
什N拥脑E[？
In a dream, you can cheat architecture
into impossible shapes.
在粞Y，你可以愚弄建BY，
⑺造成不可能的形睿
That lets you create closed loops,
like the Penrose Steps.
那可以你造出]合的路，
例如“彭_斯A梯”，
The infinite staircase.
有oF的_A。
See?
看到]有？
Paradox.
悖。
So a closed loop like that
will help you disguise...
那拥拈]合路湍阊陲…
...the boundaries of the dream you create.
…你造的舻倪界。
But how big do these levels have to be?
但@些艟有多大？
It could be anything from the floor
of a building to an entire city.
多大都可以，囊蛔建B的一
一直到整座城市。
They have to be complicated enough
that we can hide from the projections.
但是它都必足蜓}s，
那游才能躲^那些投影。
- A maze?
- Right, a maze.
- 一座迷m？
- ]e，迷m，
And the better the maze...
迷m越}s……
Then the longer we have
before the projections catch us?
那N我有越L的rg
砗屯队斑M行周旋？
Exactly.
正是。
- My subconscious seems polite enough.
- Ha, ha. You wait, they'll turn ugly.
- 俺的意R看上去都慈眉善目的。
- 哈哈，你等著瞧，他也得面目b的，
No one likes to feel someone else
messing around in their mind.
]人喜g感X有其他人
在他的^XY和。
Cobb can't build anymore, can he?
考博再也不能建造了，是幔
I don't know if he can't, but he won't.
我不知道他是否能，但是他不想。
He thinks it's safer
if he doesn't know the layouts.
他J橐是他不知道那些O，
那更安全一些。
Why?
槭颤N？
He won't tell me. But I think it's Mal.
他不告V我，我想是因。
- His ex-wife?
- No, not his ex.
- 他前妻？
- 不，不是前妻。
- They're still together?
- No.
- 他在一起幔
- 不。她…
No, she's dead.
她死了。
What you see in there
is just his projection of her.
你在那嚎吹降
只是他^X中她的投影。
What was she like in real life?
真生活中的她是怎N拥模
She was lovely.
她很可邸
- You are seeking a chemist?
- Yes.
- 你想找？
- 是的。
To formulate compounds for a job?
槟愕幕号溲u合成。
And to go into the field with us.
K和我一起加入稹
No, I rarely go into the field, Mr. Cobb.
不，我很少⒓穑考博先生。
Well, we'd need you there to tailor
compounds specific to our needs.
你看，我需要你到那槲
配u出有著特殊需求的。
- Which are?
- Great depth.
- 什N特殊需求？
- 很深的深度。
A dream within a dream? Two levels?
糁兄簦樱
Three.
三印
Not possible. That many dreams
within dreams is too unstable.
不可能。太多的糁兄很不定。
It is possible.
You just have to add a sedative.
有可能，你只要加入o┚涂梢粤恕
A powerful sedative.
力o。
- How many team members?
- Five.
- 你有T？
- 五。
Six.
六。
The only way to know you've done
the job is if I go in with you.
要t解你完成工作的情r，
只有我跟著你走。
There's no room for tourists
on a job like this, Mr. Saito.
@拥幕河^光客
可]有位置，S藤先生。
This time, it seems there is.
@一次似乎得有。
This, I think, is a good place
to start. I use it every day.
@很不e，我想可以用它，
我每天都用的。
- What for?
- Here, I'll show you.
- 有什N作用？
- ^恚我你看。
Perhaps you will not want to see.
也S你是不看的好。
After you.
你先。
Ten. Twelve.
All connected. Bloody hell.
十…十二，全B在一起。
你想得出恚
They come every day to share the dream.
他每天都磉@Y共用艟场
You see? Very stable.
看到]有？非常定。
- How long do they dream for?
- Three, four hours, each day.
- 他要做多Lrg的簦
- 三、四小r，每天。
In dream time?
糁懈杏X的rg呢？
With this compound?
About 40 hours, each and every day.
用@u？
大s每天四十小r。
- Why do they do it?
- Tell him, Mr. Cobb.
- 槭颤N他要@N做？
- 告V他，考博先生。
After a while, it becomes
the only way you can dream.
不久之後，@成了你能做舻
唯一的方式。
Do you still dream, Mr. Cobb?
你做幔考博先生？
- They come here every day to sleep?
- No.
- 他每天都磉@核X？
- 不，
They come to be woken up.
他磉@菏榱吮拘眩
The dream has become their reality.
粢呀成了他的F。
Who are you to say otherwise, sir?
l又能f得清舨皇乾F呢，嗯？
Let's see what you can do.
砜纯茨愕谋臼氯绾巍
You know how to find me.
你知道怎诱业轿遥
You know what you have to do.
你知道你做什N。
Sharp, no?
清晰幔苦牛
Are you all right, Mr. Cobb?
你]事吧，考博先生？
Yeah, yeah. Everything's just fine.
是的，]事，我很好。
Robert Fischer, heir to the Fischer
Morrow energy conglomerate.
_伯特・M希，
“M希-莫_能源集F”的^承人。
What's your problem with this Mr. Fischer?
你和@位M希先生究竟有什N}？
That's not your concern.
@不是你要P心的。
Mr. Saito, this isn't your typical
corporate espionage.
S藤先生，@…@不是你
通常的企Ig行椋
You asked me for inception.
你是要求我F“l”。
I do hope you understand
the gravity of that request.
我真的希望你能明白
@一要求的乐爻潭取
Now, the seed that we plant in
this man's mind will grow into an idea.
我要置入@人^XY的N子
成L橐意念，
This idea will define him.
@意念界定他成樵拥娜耍
It may come to change...
它也S改…
Well, it may come to change
everything about him.
它也S改他整的人。
We're the last company standing between
them and total energy dominance.
我是可以阻止他完全
主宰能源的最後的公司了，
And we can no longer compete.
但我不^他。
Soon, they'll control the energy
supply of half the world.
不久，他就⒖刂瓢世界的能源，
In effect, they become a new superpower.
事上，他正成樾碌某唷
The world needs Robert Fischer
to change his mind.
@世界需要_伯特・M希改主意。
That's where we come in.
所以我砹恕
How is Robert Fischer's relationship
with his father?
_伯特・M希c他父H的PS如何？
Rumor is the relationship
is quite complicated.
有餮哉f他的PS相}s。
Well, we can't work based
solely on rumor, can we?
但我不能H基於餮
_展工作，是幔
Can you get me access to
this man here? Browning.
你有]有k法我接近@人？白朗，
Fischer Senior's right-hand man.
Fischer Junior's godfather.
老M希的左膀右臂，
小M希的教父。
It should be possible,
if you can get the right references.
有可能，如果你能@得
m的引]信的。
References are something
of a specialty for me, Mr. Saito.
引]信可以算是我的ｉL，S藤先生。
I'm not smelling settlement here.
Take them down.
我看不出有什N解Q的可能，
把他拿下。
Mr. Browning...
白朗先生，
...Maurice Fischer's policy
is always one of avoiding litigation.
莫里斯・M希的方
一直是避免VA的。
Well, shall we voice your concerns
with Maurice directly?
好吧，那我要不要把你的]
直接告V莫里斯呢？
Not sure that's necessary.
我想不必了。
No, no, no. I think we should.
不，不，不，我想我一下。
How is he?
他怎N恿耍
I don't want to bother him
unnecessarily, but...
我不想]事打_他，但是……
Robert, I told you keep out the damn...
Wait. So do it. Get...
_伯特，我告V^你e他……
等等，快去做，去……
- Mr. Fischer.
- Put it through.
- M希先生。
- 一下。
Never, never.
Never do the same as I asked.
牟弧牟话次乙求的做。
Leave that.
e管那。
Here.
@骸
Must be a cherished memory of his.
@一定是段很珍F的。
I put it beside his bed.
He hasn't even noticed.
我把它放在他床，
他甚至都]看上一眼。
Robert...
_伯特，
...we need to talk about
a power of attorney.
我需要律的嗬，
- I know this is hard,
- Not now, Uncle Peter.
- 我知道F在@δ阌悬cy，
- F在不行，彼得大叔。
but it's imperative...
但是我必_始……
The vultures are circling.
d已在P旋，
And the sicker Maurice Fischer becomes,
莫里斯・M希病得越重，
the more powerful Peter Browning becomes.
彼得・白朗的菥驮酱蟆
I've had ample opportunity
to observe Browning...
我有了足虻rC去^察白朗，
...and adopt his physical presence,
study his mannerisms,
窦{他的wB特徵，
研究他的言e止，
and so on and so forth.
T如此不一而足。
So now in the first layer of the dream,
I can impersonate Browning.
所以在第一艟逞Y，
我可以化身白朗，
And suggest concepts
to Fischer's conscious mind.
向M希的意R^X
暗示一些概念。
Then, when we take him a level deeper...
然後，我把他入更深一艟持後，
...his own projection of Browning
should feed that right back to him.
他自己^X中投影的白朗…
把那些概念完全回o他。
So he gives himself the idea.
於是他以槟鞘撬自己的意念？
Precisely. That's the only way
it will stick.
]e。只有@硬拍芨街在他^XY，
It has to seem self-generated.
必他X得那是他自己a生的。
Eames, I am impressed.
伊姆斯，不温铩
Your condescension, as always,
is much appreciated, Arthur, thank you.
c以往一樱你的u尊降F
我是感激不M，瑟，xx。
Were you going under on your own?
你一人在做酎N？
No, no, I was just, uh, running
some experiments.
不，不，我只是在…呃…
在做一些。
I didn't realize anyone was here, so...
我]注意有e人在@海所以……
Yeah, I was just...
I was working on my totem, actually.
是啊，我…我在弄我的Dv，其。
Here, let me take a look.
^恚o我看一下。
So you're learning, huh?
@Nf你知道了，哈？
An elegant solution
for keeping track of reality.
用@拥霓k法肀eF真的很精巧。
- Was it your idea?
- No, it was, uh...
- 是你的主意幔
- 不，那是，呃…
It was Mal's, actually. This...
那其是想出淼摹＿@是…
This one was hers. She would spin it
in the dream and it would never topple.
@是她的陀螺，她在粞Y一D它，
就永h不倒，
Just spin and spin.
一直D啊D。
Arthur told me she passed away.
瑟跟我f她去世了。
How are the mazes coming along?
你的迷mO得怎N恿耍
Each level relates to the part
of the subject's subconscious...
每一佣寂c我想要接近的
主w的意R的…
...that we are trying to access.
…某一部分有M，
So I'm making the bottom level a hospital,
因此我把最底釉O成了t院，
so Fischer will bring his father.
@M希把父HУ侥茄Y，唔…
You know, I... Actually, I have
a question about this layout.
你看，我…其P於@O
我有}……
No, no, no. Don't show me specifics.
不，不，不，e…eo我看。
Only the dreamer should know the layout.
只有主粽卟胖道O方案。
Why is that so important?
槭颤N@那N重要？
In case one of us brings in
our projections.
f一我其他人
把我的投影нM粞Yr，
We don't want them knowing
the details of the maze.
我不想@些投影
知道迷m的。
You mean in case you bring Mal in.
你是ff一你把нM粞Y？
You can't keep her out, can you?
你o法不她出F，是幔
- Right.
- You can't build...
- 是的。
- 你自己不能建造它…
...because if you know the maze,
then she knows it.
是因槿绻你t解了迷m的，
她也就t解了，
Well, she'd sabotage the whole operation.
她就破恼行印
- Cobb, do the others know?
- No. No, they don't.
- 考博，其他人知道@幔
- 不，他不知道。
You've gotta warn them
if this is getting worse.
你提醒他一下，
有可能出F很糟糕的情r。
No one said it's getting worse.
不出F很糟糕的情r！
I need to get home.
That's all I care about right now.
我必回家，
@就是目前我所P心的。
Why can't you go home?
你槭颤N不能回家？
Because they think I killed her.
因樗J槭俏⒌乃。
- Thank you.
- For what?
- xx你。
- x什N？
For not asking whether I did.
x你]我是不是我⒌摹
"I will split up my father's empire."
“我要拆分我父H的帝。”
Now, this is obviously an idea that
Robert himself would choose to reject....
@@然是_伯特他自己
F在想要抗拒的意念，
...which is why we need to plant it
deep in his subconscious.
所以槭颤N我需要⑺深深地
植入到他的意R之中。
The subconscious is motivated
by emotion, right? Not reason.
意R是由感情拥模幔
而不是理智。
We need to find a way to translate
this into an emotional concept.
我需要找到某N方式
⑦@D化成感情上的概念。
How do you translate business
strategy into emotion?
你如何⒁环N商I策略D化成感情？
（莫里斯和_伯特
纱M希
煞N截然不同的I家）
That's what we're here to figure out, right?
我在@壕褪且找出k法恚N？
Robert's relationship with his father...
退一步f，_伯特c他父H的PS…
- ...is stressed, to say the least.
- Can we run with that?
- …也是相o的。
- 我能不能利用@c？
We could suggest to him
breaking up his father's company
我可以他X得
他拆分他父H的公司，
as a "screw you" to the old man.
就是老^子最好的打簦
No, because I think positive emotion
trumps negative emotion every time.
不好，因槲艺J榉eO的感情
是能龠^消O的感情，
We all yearn for reconciliation,
for catharsis.
我都渴望和解，
精神上的宣。
We need Robert Fischer...
我需要_伯特・M希…
...to have a positive
emotional reaction to all this.
…@一切a生eO的
感情上的反。
All right, well, try this. Um...
好吧，要N@，唔…
"My father accepts that I want to
create for myself,
“我父HJ可我想自己I，
not follow in his footsteps."
而不是追S他的足印。”
That might work.
@也S行。
Might? We're gonna need to do
a little better than "might".
也S？我需要比“也S”更LM一c。
Thank you for your contribution, Arthur.
噢，xx你的I，瑟。
Forgive me for wanting
a little specificity, Eames.
原我想要求一些π裕伊姆斯。
Specificity?
π裕懂幔
Inception's not about being specific.
“l”的^程可不一定那N明_，
When we get inside his mind, we're
gonna have to work with what we find.
我M入到他的^X之後，
我必WC行事才行。
On the top level, we open up
his relationship with his father...
在最上r，我_始打造
他c父Hg的PS，
...and say, "I will not follow
in my father's footsteps".
即：“我不想追S我父H的足印。”
Then the next level down, we feed him,
"I will create something for myself".
然後在下一樱我灌o他：
“我要槲易约I。”
Then, by the time we hit the bottom
level, we bring out the big guns.
然後，我到_底r，
我端出致命武器…
- "My father doesn't want me to be him."
- Exactly.
- “我父H不想我成樗。”
- 正是。
Three layers down,
the dreams are gonna collapse...
在三艟持下，
得相脆弱，
...with the slightest disturbance.
即使是最微弱的_印
Sedation.
o睡眠。
For sleep stable enough to create
three layers of dreaming...
榱造出三艟常
睡眠得足蚍定，
...we'll have to combine it with
an extremely powerful sedative.
@游必Y合用
O其诺逆o。
Good night.
晚安。
The compound we'll be using
to share the dream...
我用砉灿艟车乃…
...creates a clear connection
between dreamers...
…在主粽咧ga生
非常清晰的B接，
...whilst accelerating brain function.
同r它H上加快大X的功能。
In other words,
more time on each level.
Q句f，在每一艟持
它o我更多的rg。
Brain function in the dream will be
about 20 times normal.
糁写竽X的功能比通常要快20倍。
And when you enter a dream within
that dream, the effect is compounded.
如果你M入到糁兄簦
那效果翻番。
It's three dreams,
that's 10 hours times 20...
三粝喈於10小r乘以20……
Math was never my strong subject.
How much time is that?
Σ黄穑呃…W砭筒皇俏业，
到底是多Lrg？
It's a week, the first level down.
下面第一邮且星期，
Six months the second level down,
and the third level...
下面第二邮橇月，
第三邮恰…
That's 10 years.
10年。
Who'd wanna be stuck
in a dream for 10 years?
l意在一粞Y耗上10年？
Depends on the dream.
那得看你做什N袅恕
So once we've made the plant,
how do we get out?
那N我一旦完成任眨
我怎N回砟兀
I'm hoping you have something more
elegant than shooting me in the head.
我希望你已有了更文明的k法，
而不是朝我^上_一？
- A kick.
- What's a kick?
- 用反_/踢。
- 什N是反_？
This, Ariadne, would be a kick.
@，阿Y阿德涅，就叫反_。
It's that feeling of falling you get
that jolts you awake.
感X到落就⒛阏鹦眩
Snaps you out of the dream.
使你猛然x艟场
Are we gonna feel a kick
with this sedation?
用了那N力的o┽
我能感X到反_幔
That's the clever part.
噢，妙就妙在@Y，
I customized the sedative to leave
inner-ear function unimpaired.
我特u的o┎影
榷【平衡感X器】的功能，
That way, however deep the sleep,
the sleeper still feels falling.
那右恚o你的睡眠有多深，
你仍然能感X到落，
Or tipping.
或翻倒。
The trick is to synchronize a kick
that can penetrate all three levels.
PIc是要使反_同步，
而且它能穿越所有三艟场
We could use a musical countdown
to synchronize the different kicks.
我可以利用音返涤r器
硗步不同鹊姆_。
He hasn't got any surgery
scheduled, no dental, nothing.
他]有任何的手g安排、
看牙t的安排，什N都]有。
Wasn't he supposed to have
a knee operation?
他不是需要做膝w手g幔
Nothing. Nothing that they'll
put him under for, anyway. And we need...
]有，]有什N能有C
他睡眠。我需要…
We need at least a good 10 hours.
我至少需要足的10小r。
Sydney to Los Angeles.
悉尼到洛杉，
One of the longest flights in the world.
世界上最L的w行rg之一，
He makes it every two weeks.
他每尚瞧诙家w一趟。
He must be flying private, then.
那他也是用他的私人wC。
Not if there were unexpected
maintenance with his plane.
要是他的私人wC需要
意外S修的就不行了。
- It would have to be a 747.
- Why's that?
- 那就需要一架波音747。
- 槭颤N？
On a 747, the pilot's up top...
因747上w行T在上面，
...the first-class cabin's in the nose,
so no one would walk through.
^等位於C^，
所以]有人走碜呷ァ
You'd have to buy out the entire cabin
and the first-class flight attendant.
不^你得I下整^等，
以及^等的服杖T。
I bought the airline.
我I下了航空公司，
It seemed neater.
那雍孟窀乾脆。
Well, looks like we have our 10 hours.
@下我有了需要的十小r了。
Ariadne? Terrific work, by the way.
阿Y阿德涅？α耍值煤馨簟
You know how to find me.
你知道怎诱业轿遥
You know what you have to do.
你知道你做什N。
You remember when you asked me
to marry you?
你得你r是
怎酉蛭仪蠡榈幔
Of course I do.
我然得。
You said you had a dream.
你f你做了簟
That we'd grow old together.
舻轿一起老。
And we can.
我可以。
You shouldn't be here.
你不磉@Y。
Just wanted to see what kind of tests
you're doing on your own every night.
我只是想看一下每晚你自
都在做些什N拥脑。
- This has nothing to do with you.
- This has everything to do with me.
- @和你]有PS。
- 然和我有PS，
You've asked me
to share dreams with you.
是你要求我分享你的艟车摹
Not these. These are my dreams.
不包括@些，@些是我人的簟
Why do you do this to yourself?
槭颤N你要@N做？
It's the only way I can still dream.
因檫@是我仍然能做舻奈ㄒ晦k法。
Why is it so important to dream?
槭颤N做裟屈N重要？
In my dreams, we're still together.
在我的粞Y，我仍然在一起。
These aren't just dreams.
@些不HH是簦
These are memories.
And you said never to use memories.
@些是你的。
你f^Q不能用的。
I know I did.
我知道我f^。
You're trying to keep her alive.
You can't let her go.
你D想她活著，
你不λ放手。
You don't understand.
These are moments I regret.
你不理解，
@些r刻，是我感到z憾的r刻；
They're memories that I have to change.
@些，是我必改的。
Well, what's down there that you regret?
那N那下面有什N使你z憾的呢？
Listen, there's only one thing
you need to understand about me.
著，P於我你只需
理解一件事就行了。
This is your house?
@是你/你的房子？
Mine and Mal's, yes.
我和的，是的。
Where is she?
她在哪海
She's already gone.
她已走了。
That's my son, James.
那是我鹤樱詹姆士。
He's digging for something, maybe a worm.
他在挖什N|西，也S是lx子。
That's Phillipa.
那是菲利帕。
I thought about calling out to them...
你知道我r想λ大喊，
...so they'd turn and smile
and I could see...
那铀就D^^硐蛭椅⑿Γ
我就可以看清那…
...those beautiful faces of theirs,
but it's all too late.
…那美的面孔。
但是…一切都太晚了。
Right now or never, Cobb.
立刻就走，不然就e想走了，考博。
Then I start to panic.
然後我_始@慌，
I realize I'm gonna regret
this moment...
我意R到我不想檫@一刻
而感到後悔，
...that I need to see their faces
one last time.
我需要最後一次
再看一眼他的面孔。
James! Phillipa! Come on in!
詹姆士！菲利帕！快M恚
But the moment's past.
但@一刻^去了。
And whatever I do,
I can't change this moment.
o我做什N
都不能改@一刻。
As I'm about to call out to them...
我想_他大喊一r，
...they run away.
他s跑_了。
If I'm ever gonna see their faces
again, I've gotta get back home.
如果我想再到他的面孔，
我必要回家去，
The real world.
在真的世界。
What are you doing here?
你磉@Y致铮
My name is...
我是……
I know who you are.
What are you doing here?
我知道你是l。
你磉@Y质颤N？
I'm just trying to understand.
我只是想理解。
How could you understand?
你怎N能蚶斫猓
Do you know what it is to be a lover?
你知道成廴怎幔
To be half of a whole?
成檎w的一半？
No.
不知道。
I'll tell you a riddle.
我碜你猜一liZ：
You're waiting for a train.
你在等一列火，
A train that will take you far away.
一列你去向h方的火。
You know where you hope
this train will take you...
你知道你希望@列火
你去向何方，
...but you don't know for sure.
但是你不能_定，
But it doesn't matter.
不^那也]PS。
How can it not matter to you
where that train will take you?
@列火你去向哪里，
怎N跟你]PS呢？
Because you'll be together.
因槟在一起。
- How could you bring her here, Dom?
- What is this place?
- 你怎N能她磉@Y，多姆？
- @是什N地方？
This is a hotel suite where we
used to spend our anniversary.
@是店的套房，
我在Y婚o念日住^。
What happened here?
@Yl生^什N事？
You promised!
You promised we'd be together!
你答^！
你SZ^我在一起！
Please, I need you to stay here
just for now!
Σ黄穑我需要你留在@Y，
r@樱
You said we'd be together!
You said we'd grow old together!
你f^我在一起！
你f^我一起老！
I'll come back for you. I promise.
我再回淼模我保C。
Do you think you can just build
a prison of memories to lock her in?
你以槟憬ㄒ蛔的Oz
就能把她i在Y面幔
Do you really think that
that's gonna contain her?
你真的以槟泳湍芟拗谱∷幔
It's time.
是r候了。
Maurice Fischer just died in Sydney.
莫里斯・M希在悉尼去世。
- When's the funeral?
- Thursday. In Los Angeles.
- 葬Y是什Nr候？
- 星期四，在洛杉。
Robert should accompany the body
no later than Tuesday. We should move.
_伯特在L二之前
o送他的zw回去。我行恿恕
All right.
是啊。
- Cobb, I'm coming with you.
- I promised Miles. No.
- 考博，我和你一起去？
- 我答^~斯。不行。
The team needs someone...
Y需要有人…
...who understands
what you're struggling with.
…t解你暝的是什N。
And it doesn't have to be me...
不一定非得是我，
...but then you have to show Arthur
what I just saw.
那你必瑟看看
我才看到的一切。
Get us another seat on the plane.
在wC上o我多安排一位置。
If I get on this plane
and you don't honor our agreement...
一旦我踏上@架wC，
而你不履行我的fh，
...when we land,
I go to jail for the rest of my life.
那我著以後，
我就被PMOz呆下半子。
Complete the job en route...
旅途中完成任蔗幔
...I make one phone call
from the plane...
我娘wC上打一，
...you have no trouble
getting through Immigration.
你就能毫o障K地通^入境。
- I'm sorry.
- Oh, yeah, absolutely.
- Σ黄稹
- 噢，抱歉，然。
Thank you.
xx。
（“系安全А纾
Excuse me, I think this is yours?
You must have dropped it.
Σ黄穑我想@是你的？
你可能才掉的。
Would you care for a drink?
先生想要喝c什N幔
Oh. Water, please.
噢，o我水。
Oh, um, same, please.
噢，嗯，一樱xx。
Um...
唔…
Thank you.
xx你。
You know, I couldn't help but notice...
你看，我]忍住好奇注意到…
...but you wouldn't happen to be related
to the Maurice Fischer, would you?
…你和那位莫里斯・M希
好像有什NPS，幔
Yes, he, um...
是的，他是…唔…
He was my father.
他是我父H。
Well, he was a very inspiring figure.
I'm sorry for your loss.
噢，他是非常令人振^的人物，
很z憾你失去了他。
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
- @是你的。
- xx。
Hey.
嘿，
To your father.
槟愀赣H，
May he rest in peace, huh?
他安息。
- Couldn't have peed before you went under?
- Sorry.
- 下碇前你就不能去撒尿？
- 抱歉。
Bit too much free champagne before takeoff?
起w前免M香喝多了吧，尤素福？
Ha, ha, bloody ha.
哈哈，好O了。
We know he's gonna be looking
for a taxi in this weather.
@拥奶猓我知道他一定
在想找一v程。
- Asshole! Hey, man, why don't you try...?
- Walk away.
- 混蛋！嘿，槭颤N你不……？
- W_。
Just have him ca... I gotta go.
就他打……我得炝恕
All right. Taxi. Thank you.
好的。程！xx。
All right, Third and Market. Snappy.
好的，第三街和市鼋帧Ｋ！
- What are you doing?
- Sorry, I thought it was free.
- 你想致铮
- Σ黄穑我以槭强哲。
- It's not.
- Maybe we could share.
- 不，不空。
- 也S我可以拼一下。
Maybe not.
Can you pull over and get this...?
也S不行。
麻┠惆衍停一下，@……
Great.
好O了。
Come on.
快c。
There's $500 in there.
The wallet's worth more than that.
@Y面有500美元，
X包不止@r。
You might at least drop me at my stop.
所以我到了你至少我下。
I'm afraid that it doesn't...
恐怕那不……
- Cover him!
- Down! Down now!
- 掩o他！
- 趴下！快趴下！
What the hell is going on?
@他的怎N回事？
This wasn't in the design.
@不是我的OY的。
Cobb?
考博？
Get him!
值羲！
Are you all right?
你]事吧？
Yeah, I'm okay. I'm okay.
是的，我]事，我很好，我很好。
Fischer's okay, unless he gets carsick.
M希也很好，只要]就好。
Saito?
S藤？
Get Fischer in the back room now.
把M希У结崦娣块g去，快。
- Get him in the back room. Move.
- What the hell happened?
- 把他У结崦娣块g去，快c！
- 怎N回事？
Has he been shot? Is he dying?
他中了幔克快死了幔
- I don't know.
- Jesus Christ.
- 我不知道。
- 天哪！
- What happened to you?
- Blocked by a freight train.
- 你才在那海磕阍觞N回事？
- 我被一列\列踝×恕
Why put a train in a
downtown intersection?
你槭颤N在[市十字路口
放上一列Mn直撞的火？
- I didn't.
- Where'd it come from?
- 我]放。
- 那它是打哪淼模
Why the hell were we ambushed?
我有}要你呢！
槭颤N他的我遭到伏簦哈？
Those were not normal projections.
They'd been trained, for God's sakes.
那些不是他正常的投影，
他他的接受^！
- You're right.
- How could he be trained?
- 你f得Α
- 他怎N接受^？
Fischer's had an extractor teach
his subconscious to defend itself,
M希提取者
教^他意R的防R，
so his subconscious is militarized.
所以他的意R是事化的。
It should've shown in the research.
@事先做好功n。Σ黄稹
- Why the hell didn't it?
- Calm down.
- 那你他的怎N]做？
- 冷o。
Don't tell me to calm down!
e告V我要冷o！
This was your job, goddamn it!
This was your responsibility!
@是你做的工作，鬼！
@是你的任！
You were meant to check
Fischer's background!
你氐z查^M希的背景！
We are not prepared for this type of...
我可]檫@拥慕换鹱龊洌
We have dealt with sub-security before!
我以前也理^意R防R，
We'll be more careful
and we're gonna be fine!
只要我更加小心一c，
我]事的。
This was not a part of the plan!
He's dying.
“以前”不是@的一部分！
他快死了，老天哪！
Put him out his misery.
我退x苦海。
- No, don't do that! Don't do that.
- Cobb, hey, hey.
- e那N做！e那N做！
- 考博，嘿，嘿。
He's in agony. I'm waking him up.
他@雍芡纯啵我想拘阉。
No. It won't wake him up.
不，那静恍阉。
What do you mean, it won't wake him up?
When we die in a dream, we wake up.
你什N意思，那静恍阉？
我在糁兴廊ィ我就醒了。
Not from this.
不能倪@粞Y。
We're too heavily sedated
to wake up that way.
我的o┯玫锰重，
不能以那拥姆绞叫怼
Right. So, what happens when we die?
好啊，那N我死了l生什N呢？
- We drop into limbo.
- Are you serious?
- 我入U界。
- 你]_玩笑吧？
- Limbo?
- Unconstructed dream space.
- U界？
- 未建的艟场
- Well, what the hell is down there?
- Just raw, infinite subconscious.
- 那下面究竟有什N？
- 只有原始的o限的意R。
Nothing is down there, except for
what might have been left behind...
下面什N都]有，
除了有人以前共用艟车r候，
...by anyone sharing the dream
who's been trapped there before.
被困在那Y而可能留下的
不管什N|西，
Which, in our case, is just you.
於我碚f，只有你去^。
- How long could we be stuck?
- Can't even think about trying to escape...
- 可我有可能被困在那憾嗑茫
- 想都e想逃出恚
- ...until the sedation...
- How long?
- 直到o┑乃效p弱……
- 多久？
Decades. It could be infinite.
Ask him, he's the one who's been there.
资年，也So限期，我哪知道。
他好了，只有他去^。
Let's get him upstairs.
我把他抬到上面去。
Great.
太棒了。
Thank you.
xx你。
So now we're trapped in Fischer's mind,
battling his own private army.
@NfF在我被困在了M希^XY，
和他的私人搏著命，
And if we get killed...
而一旦我被⑺溃
...we'll be lost in limbo till our brains
turn to scrambled egg, hmm?
我就迷失在U界之中
直到我的X子成炒蛋，嗯？
Someone got first aid?
有急救用品幔
So, you knew about these risks
and you didn't tell us?
@Nf你知道有@些LU，
而你]有告V我？
There weren't meant to be any risks.
原聿有什NLU，
- I didn't know we'd be dealing with gunfire.
- You had no right.
- 我]料到遭遇那N激烈的稹
- 你]嗬@N做。
This was the only way
to go three layers deep.
只有@游才能深入三艟场
You knew about this
and went along with it?
有你，你也早知道了，
s默不吱？
I trusted him.
我信任他啊。
When? When he promised you
half his share?
你信任他？什Nr候？
他答分一半Xo你？
No. His whole share.
Besides, he said he'd done it before.
不是，他那份全o我。
再f，他f他以前做^。
What, with Mal?
Because that worked so good?
你以前做^？和l？和？
有什N好Y果]？
That has nothing to do with it.
那和F在]PS。
I did what I had to
to get back to my children.
我做了我做的，
我要回到我的孩子身。
You led us into a war zone
with no way out?
所以你就把我拖入了
]有出路的觯
There is a way out, all right?
有出路的，知道幔
We continue on with the job,
and we do it as fast as possible...
我^m绦羞@一任眨
K且快地完成，
...and we get out using the kick,
just like before.
到r候用反_，把我С艟常
就像以前一印
Forget it. We go any deeper,
we just raise the stakes.
我歇了。如果我深入下去，
只遇到更多LU。
I am sitting this one out on this level.
我就在@一由献一小r，更糟幔
Fischer's security is
surrounding this place.
我@诱，M希的意Rl
已包@地方。
Ten hours of flight time
is a week at this level.
十小r的w行rg，
在@一由暇褪且星期。
That means each and every one
of us will be killed.
那就是f我每一人
都死在@Y，
That I can guarantee you.
@一c我可以保C。
We have no other choice
but to continue on
我]有e的x瘢
只有^m下去，
and do it as fast as possible.
K快完成任铡
Downwards is the only way forwards.
往下，是往前的唯一出路。
Get ready.
浜谩
You, come on. Let's go shake him up.
你，走吧，我去震一震他。
I'm insured against kidnapping
for up to 10 million.
我上了高_一千f的防架U，
- This should be very simple.
- Shut up! It won't be.
- 所以@很巍
- ]嘴！]那N巍
In your father's office,
below the bookshelves...
在你父H的k公室Y，
架下I…
...is his personal safe.
We need the combination.
…是他的私人保U。
我需要它的密a。
I don't know any safe.
我不知道有什N保U。
That doesn't mean
you don't know the combination.
那K不代表你不知道密a。
Tell us what it is.
告V我那是什N。
I don't know.
我不知道。
We have it on good authority you do know.
我有嗤的消息碓矗他你肯定知道。
Yeah? Whose authority?
是幔嗤是l？
- Five hundred dollars, this cost.
- What's inside it?
- @值五百美元。
- Y面有什N？
Cash, cards, ID. And this.
F金、各N卡、身份C、有@。
Useful?
有用幔
Maybe.
也S。
You're on. You've got an hour.
你出霭桑o你一小r。
An hour?
一小r？
I was supposed to have all night
to crack this.
我本有整晚上砬怂的嘴。
And Saito wasn't supposed
to be shot in the chest.
S藤本聿胸前中。
You've got one hour,
now get us something useful, please.
就一小r，弄出c有用的|西，拜了。
- What's that?
- Good authority.
- 那是什N？
- 嗤啊。
Uncle Peter.
彼得大叔。
Just make them stop.
…他住手。
- The combination.
- I don't know it.
- 密a？
- 我真的不知道。
- Why does Browning say you do?
- I don't know.
- 槭颤N白朗f你知道？
- 我不知道。
Just let me talk to him and I'll find out.
我和他，看看怎N回事。
You have one hour. Start talking.
你有一小r，_吧。
You all right?
你]事吧？
You okay?
你好吧？
Those bastards have had at me for two days.
@些混蛋已P了我商炝恕
They have someone with access
to your father's office.
他有人J入了你父H的k公室，
- They're trying to open his safe.
- Yeah.
- 想打_他的保U。
- 是幔
They thought I'd know the combination,
but I don't know it.
他以槲抑道密a，
但是我真的不知道。
- Yeah, well, neither do I, so...
- What?
- 是啊，我也不知道，所以……
- 什N？
Maurice told me that when he passed,
you were the only one able to open it.
莫里斯跟我f在他去世後，
你是唯一能打_它的人。
No, he never gave me any combination.
不，他]…他]o^我什N密a。
Maybe he did. I mean, maybe you
just didn't know it was a combination.
也S他f^，我是f，
也S只是你不知道那是密a。
Well, what, then?
那是什N？
I don't know, some meaningful
combination of numbers...
我不知道，一些有意x的滴唤M合，
...based on your experiences with Maurice.
基於你…你c莫里斯以往的v。
We didn't have very many, uh,
meaningful experiences together.
我]有S多…唔…
有意x的共同v。
Perhaps after your mother died.
也S在你母H去世後就少了。
After my mother died,
you know what he told me?
我母H去世後，
你知道他ξ艺f什N？
"Robert, there's really nothing to be said."
“_伯特，我真的]什N可f的。”
Oh, well, he was bad with emotion.
噢，他不善於表露感情。
I was 11, Uncle Peter.
我才11q啊，彼得大叔。
- How's he doing?
- He's in a lot of pain.
- 他怎N恿耍
- 他很痛苦。
When we get down to the lower levels,
the pain will be less intense.
我到_下面的滇幔
疼痛就]那N×伊恕
And if he dies?
要是他死了呢？
Worst-case scenario?
最牡那r？
When he wakes up,
his mind is completely gone.
他醒^磲幔
他的^XY一片空白。
Cobb, I'll still honor the arrangement.
考博，我仍然履行我的fh。
I appreciate that, Saito.
我很感x你@Nf，S藤，
But when you wake up, you won't even
remember that we had an arrangement.
可是你醒^硪葬幔
你都不得我有^fh。
Limbo is gonna become your reality.
U界就成了你的F。
You're gonna be lost down there so long
that you're gonna become an old man.
你在那下I迷失得如此L久，
以至於成一老人。
Filled with regret?
心中充Mz憾？
Waiting to die alone.
在孤中等待死亡。
No.
不，
I'll come back.
我回淼摹
And we'll be young men together again.
我得年p，再一次在一起。
Breathe.
深呼吸。
These people are gonna kill us
if we don't give them the combination.
@些人在@⒘宋，
如果我不o他密a。
- They just wanna ransom us.
- I heard them.
- 他只是想要H金。
- 我到他f了，
They're gonna lock us in that van,
and then drive it into the river.
他浒盐iM那vI包Y，
然後_M河Y。
All right. What is in the safe?
好吧，保UY到底是什N？
Something for you.
是o你的|西。
Maurice always said it was
his most precious gift to you.
莫里斯是f那是
他留o你的最珍F的Y物。
- A will.
- Maurice's will is with Port and Dunn.
- 一份z凇
- 莫里斯的z谠凇波特-恩事账”。
That's an alternate.
那只是A浒姹尽
This would supersede the other
if you want it to.
@一份可以替Q那一份，
如果你意的。
It splits up the component businesses
of Fischer Morrow.
@一份的热菔
拆分“M希-莫_”的子公司，
It'd be the end of the entire empire
as we know it.
Y束我F在作
帝存在的整集F。
Destroying my whole inheritance?
У粑业娜部za？
- Why would he suggest such a thing?
- I just don't know.
- 槭颤N他要建h@幼觯
- 我也不知道。
He loved you, Robert.
他勰悖_伯特，
In his own way.
以他自己的方式。
以他自己的方式？
At the end...
RK前，
...he called me in to his deathbed.
他把我叫到他床，
He could barely speak.
他已缀跽f不出了，
But he took the trouble
to tell me one last thing.
但是他是拼M力猓
告V了我最後一件事。
He pulled me close.
他我靠近他，
And I could only make out...
我只能分辨出…
...one word.
…一~――
"Disappointed."
“失望”。
When were you in limbo?
你什Nr候到^U界？
You might have the rest of the team
convinced to carry on with this job.
你怎N能在其他T
都不明真相的情r下，f服他…
- But they don't know the truth.
- Truth? What truth?
- …绦羞@任眨
- 真相？什N真相？
The truth that, at any minute,
真相就是SrS刻，
you might bring a freight train
through the wall.
你都有可能Y
拽出一v\列；
The truth that Mal is bursting
through your subconscious.
真相就是正在
你的意RY大爆l；
And the truth that,
as we go deeper into Fischer...
真相就是S著我越深地
M入_伯特的^X，
...we're also going deeper into you.
我也就越深地M入你的^X。
And I'm not sure
we're gonna like what we find.
我不_定我芬饪吹
我lF的|西。
We were working together.
我曾一起工作，
We were exploring the concept
of a dream within a dream.
我曾一起探索糁兄舻母拍睢
I kept pushing things.
我是非常急切，
I wanted to go deeper and deeper.
I wanted to go further.
我希望走得越碓缴睿
我希望超越O限。
I just didn't understand the concept...
我r不明白…
...that hours could turn
into years down there...
…在那下面，小r成啄辏
...that we could get trapped so deep...
我陷得如此之深，
...that when we wound up on the shore
of our own subconscious...
最K到_了我自己的
意R的彼岸，
...we lost sight of what was real.
我失去了分辨真的界。
We created.
We built the world for ourselves.
我槲自己，
造和建立了一世界。
We did that for years.
我至撕芏嗄辏
We built our own world.
我建成了我自己的世界。
How long were you stuck there?
你在那Y停留了多Lrg？
Something like 50 years.
大概有50年吧。
Jesus.
天哪，
How could you stand it?
你怎N受得了的？
It wasn't so bad at first,
feeling like gods.
一_始K不太糟，
扇烁杏X像是神一印
The problem was knowing that
none of it was real.
}是t解到@一切
都不是真的。
Eventually, it just became impossible
for me to live like that.
最後，我K於感X到
我不能再像那由活了。
And what about for her?
那她怎N樱
She had locked something away,
something deep inside her.
她把什N|西i了起恚
深深地i在了她的^XY。
A truth that she had once known,
but chose to forget.
她曾知道什N是真相，
但是她x窳诉z忘。
Limbo became her reality.
U界成了她的F。
What happened when you woke up?
那你醒磲嵊职l生了什N？
Well, to wake up from that
after years, after decades...
哪拥慕v了啄辍
资年的感X中醒恚
...to become old souls thrown back
into youth like that?
就像是n老的`魂重又
塞回了年p人的|w。
I knew something was wrong with her.
She just wouldn't admit it.
我知道她有什N地方得不牛
只是她不意承J。
Eventually, she told me the truth.
K於，她向我f出了真相――
She was possessed by an idea.
她已被一意念牢牢控制。
This one very simple idea
that changed everything.
@一非常蔚囊饽睿
改了一切，
That our world wasn't real.
那就是我的世界不是真的，
That she needed to wake up
to come back to reality...
她需要醒^砘氐浆F去……
...that in order to get back home...
榱嘶氐浆F中的家，
...we had to kill ourselves.
我必⑺牢自己。
- What about your children?
- She thought they were projections...
- 那你的孩子怎N解？
- 她J樗是我意R的投影，
...that our real children were waiting
for us up there somewhere.
而我真的孩子
在上面的家中等著我。
- I'm their mother!
- Calm down.
- 我是他的母H！
- o。
I can tell the difference.
你不J槲铱梢苑直娉鏊不一幔
If this is my dream,
why can't I control this?
如果@是我的簦
槭颤N我控制不了@？
You don't know you're dreaming!
因槟悴恢道你正在做簦
She was certain
there was nothing I could do...
她的B度如此Q^，
我o能榱Γ
...no matter how much I begged,
no matter how much I pleaded.
不管我如何┣螅
不管我如何乞求。
She wanted to do it,
but she could not do it alone.
她Q定要做，
但是她又不能自去做。
She loved me too much, so she came up
with a plan on our anniversary.
她畚姨深，於是…
她想出了@我Y婚o念日的。
- Sweetheart, what are you doing?
- Join me.
- H鄣模你在致铮
- 和我一起怼
Just... Just step back inside.
All right?
先…先退回到屋Y，行幔
Just step back inside now,
come on.
先退回到屋Y。快c。
No. I'm going to jump,
and you're coming with me.
不。我要跳下去了，
你和我一起幔
No, I'm not.
不，我不。
Now, you listen to me.
F在…F在你我f，
If you jump, you're not gonna wake up,
remember? You're gonna die.
如果你跳下去，你不醒淼摹
你想想？你死去。
Now, just step back inside.
F在就…就退回到屋Y。
Come on. Step back inside
so we can talk about this.
快c！往後退到屋子Y，
@游才可以一下。
We've talked enough.
我已^太多了。
- Mal.
- Come out onto the ledge...
- 。
- 出碚镜M架上，
- ...or I'll jump right now.
- Okay.
- 不然我F在就跳了。
- 好的。
We're gonna talk about this.
我就@，
All right?
好幔
- I'm asking you to take a leap of faith.
- No, honey.
- 我是在要求你硪信心上的wS。
- 不，H鄣摹
No, I can't. You know I can't do that.
不，我不能，你知道我不能那N做。
Take a second,
think about our children.
花一秒想想我的孩子，
Think about James.
想想詹姆士，
Think about Phillipa, now.
想想菲利帕。
If I go without you,
they'll take them away anyway.
如果我自己跳下去了，
孩子也被ё叩摹
- What does that mean?
- I filed a letter with our attorney...
- 你@什N意思？
- 我o我的律留下一封信，
...explaining how I'm fearful
for my safety.
明t我多N槲业陌踩心，
How you've threatened to kill me.
有你是如何威{要⒘宋摇
- Why did you do this?
- I love you, Dom.
- 你槭颤N@N做？
- 我勰悖多姆。
Why did? Why would you
do this to me?
槭颤N你…槭颤N…
槭颤N你要如此Υ我？
I've freed you from the guilt
of choosing to leave them.
榱耸鼓忝獬因檫x耠x_他
而a生的染巍
We're going home
to our real children.
我要回家了，
回到我真的孩子身。
Oh, no, no, no, Mal, you listen to me,
all right? Mal, look at me, please?
噢，不，不…不，。你我f，行幔
，你看著我，求求你了！
You're waiting for a train.
你在等一列火，
- Mal, goddamn it, don't do this!
- A train that will take you far away.
- ，上帝啊！e@N做！
- 一列你去向h方的火。
James and Phillipa are waiting for you!
詹姆士和菲利帕在等著你！
You know where you hope
this train will take you...
你知道你希望@列火
你去向何方，
- They're waiting for us!
- ...but you can't know for sure.
- 他正在等著我！
- 但是你不能_定，
- Mal, look at me!
- But it doesn't matter.
- ，看著我啊！
- 不^那也]PS。
- Mal, goddamn it! Mal, listen to me!
- Because you'll be together.
- ，鬼！
- 因槟在一起。
Sweetheart! Look at me! Mal, no!
H鄣模】纯次遥！不！
Jesus Christ!
耶d・基督啊！
She had herself declared sane
by three different psychiatrists.
她找了三不同的精神病t生，
C明她的精神是健康的，
It made it impossible for me to try
to explain the nature of her madness.
那游揖筒豢赡芙忉
@一切都源自於她的狂。
So I ran.
於是，我亡命天涯。
Right now, or never, Cobb.
立刻就走，不然就e想走了，考博。
James! Phillipa! Come on in! Come on!
詹姆士！菲利帕！快M恚】禳c！
All right, let's go.
好吧，我走。
I left my children behind and I've been
trying to buy my way back ever since.
我x_了我的孩子，哪且豢唐穑
我or不在努力想回到他身。
Your guilt defines her.
It's what powers her.
你的染嗡茉炝怂，
使她活S在你的^X中。
But you are not responsible
for the idea that destroyed her.
但是你不
е滤绲囊饽钬。
And if we are gonna succeed in this...
如果我想成功完成@次任眨
...you have to forgive yourself,
and you're gonna have to confront her.
你必原你自己，
你必勇敢地直面她。
But you don't have to do that alone.
然你不必自一人去面Α
- No, you're not...
- I'm doing it for the others.
- 不，你不用……
- 我@幼鍪榱似渌人，
Because they have no idea...
因樗全然不知…
...the risk they've taken
coming down here with you.
…和你一起淼较旅嫠要冒的LU。
We have to move.
我得走了。
Time's up.
rg到。
All right. I don't know any combination.
好吧，我不知道任何的密a，
- Not consciously, anyway.
- How about instinctively, huh?
- 至少意RY]有。
- 那本能反Y呢，嗯？
I got somebody
in your father's office right now...
我F在就有人站在
你父H的k公室Y，
...ready to tap in the combination.
要漭入密a。
Give me the first six numbers
that come to your head right now.
o我此刻在你^XY
冒出淼念^六底帧
- I have no idea.
- Right now!
- 我不知道。
- 就F在！
I said, right now! Right now!
我f了就是此刻！快f！
Five, two, eight, four, nine, one.
5…2…8…491。
You'll have to do better than that.
你要做得更好才行。
All right. Bag them.
You're going for a ride.
行了，把他罩起怼
要你去兜兜L。
We're worth more to you alive.
You hear me?
我活著δ更值X。
我f的幔
What'd you get?
得到什N了？
Relationship with his father
is worse than we imagined.
那孩子c他父H的PS
比我想像的要糟。
This helps us how?
@ξ有用幔
The stronger the issues,
the more powerful the catharsis.
}越乐兀
精神上的宣作用也越。
- How are we gonna reconcile them?
- I'm working on that.
- 你打算如何和他之g如此巨大的疏x？
- 我正想k法呢，急什N？
Work faster.
The projections are closing in quick.
最好快c，他的投影
已很快包了我，
We gotta break out of here
before we're totally boxed in.
我得倪@和怀鋈ィ
免得被他在@Y。
Damn it.
的！
You mustn't be afraid to dream
a little bigger, darling.
你不害怕做一
稍微宏大一c的簦H鄣摹
We need to shift his animosity
from his father to his godfather.
我需要他把骋乃父H身上
D移到他教父身上。
Destroy his one positive relationship?
@不Я怂唯一比^eO的PS？
No, we repair his relationship
with his father...
不，我通^揭露他教父的真面目，
...whilst exposing his godfather's
true nature.
硇退c他父H的PS。
We should charge Fischer a lot more
than Saito for this job.
我在M希身上
榨出比S藤o我的多。
His security is gonna
get worse as we go deeper.
他的意Rl怎樱
我深入下去後情r更糟。
- I think we run with Mr. Charles.
- No.
- 我想我可以一查理斯先生。
- 不行。
- Who's Mr. Charles?
- Bad idea.
- l是查理斯先生？
- t主意。
The second we get into that hotel
his security's gonna be all over us.
我一到_那家店，想接近M希，
他的l就oS著我。
We run with Mr. Charles
like on the Stein job.
我用查理斯先生，
就像在斯坦因那一次做的那印
- You've done it before?
- Yeah, and it didn't work.
- @Nf你z以前诌^？
- 是的，不^根本]起作用，
The subject realized he was dreaming
and his subconscious tore us to pieces.
主w意R到他在做簦
他的意R差c]把我撕成碎片。
Excellent.
But you learned a lot, right?
太好了，你W到了不少，幔
- I need some kind of distraction.
- No problem.
- 我需要有人替我干_一下。
- ]}，
How about a lovely lady
that I've used before?
用一下我以前用^的一位
可鄣呐士怎N樱
Listen to me.
You drive carefully, all right?
我f，你小心c_，知道幔
Everything down there is
gonna be unstable as hell.
下面的情rO不定。
Don't jump too soon.
e提前跳。
We only got one shot at that kick.
We gotta make it.
反_r我只有一次C，
我必成功。
I'll play the music to let you know
it's coming. The rest is on you.
我播放音纷你知道要反_了。
其N的就全靠你自己了。
- You ready?
- Ready!
- 浜昧幔
- 好了！
Sweet dreams.
做好簦
Am I boring you?
我你X得┝幔
I was telling you my story.
I guess it wasn't to your liking.
我在跟你v我的故事，
但你好像K不太喜g。
Um, I have a lot on my mind.
噢，唔…我心Y有事。
There goes Mr. Charles.
查理斯先生出隽恕
Mr. Fischer, right?
M希先生？幔
Pleasure to see you again.
Rod Green from marketing. I...
很高d又到你，
我是行N部的_德・格林。我……
Hmm.
嗯。
- And you must be?
- Leaving.
- @位是……？
- 正好要走。
In case you get bored.
要是你X得o聊了……
Must've blown you off.
她在跟你扯淡呢，
That is, unless her phone number
really is only six digits.
除非她的a
真的只有六位怠
（“528-491”）
Funny way to make friends,
someone stealing your wallet like that.
@下I真有意思，
YR朋友那油的愕腻X包。
Goddamn it. The wallet alone
is worth at least 500...
哈，鬼！X包本身就至少值500……
About $500, right?
大s500美元，幔
Don't worry about it. My people
are already on it as we speak.
你看，你不用心。我的r候，
我的人已_始行恿恕
Who or what is Mr. Charles?
l是查理斯先生，有什N用？
It's a gambit designed to turn Fischer
against his own subconscious.
@是榱苏T使M希抗
他自己的意R而O出的一招。
And why don't you approve?
你槭颤NJ檫@是t主意？
It involves telling the mark
that he's dreaming...
因檫@涉及到
要告V我的目怂在做簦
...which involves attracting
a lot of attention to us.
於是也o我招砗芏嗄抗狻
- Didn't Cobb say never to do that?
- Hmm.
- 考博不是f^不能@N做幔
- 嗯，
So now you've noticed how much time...
@下你也注意到了，
...Cobb spends doing things
he says never to do.
考博常出反。
Mr. Saito, can I have a moment?
S藤先生，你有rg幔
- I'm sorry, but...
- Hold on! Wait!
- 噢，我…Σ黄穑但是……
- 等一下！等等！
You look a bit perkier.
你看上去神恻c了。
Very amusing, Mr. Eames.
非常有趣，伊姆斯先生。
Turbulence on the plane?
wC遇到饬髁耍
No, it's much closer.
不，是更近的原因，
That's Yusuf's driving.
是尤素福_的。
Um, I'm sorry.
Who did you say you were?
呃…Σ黄穑你f你是l碇？
Rod Green from marketing.
行N部的_德・格林。
But that's not true at all, is it?
那完全不是事，幔
My name is Mr. Charles.
You remember me, don't you?
我的名字是查理斯先生，
你得我的，幔
I'm the head of your security down here.
我是你在下面的安全的。
Get out on a different floor,
keep moving.
在不同的映鋈ィ
然後^m走。
Dump the wallet.
Security will be looking for that.
扔掉X包，保安去找的。
- Okay.
- We need to buy Cobb a little more time.
- 好的。
- 我需要替考博多取crg。
Security, huh?
安全，哈？
- You work for the hotel?
- No, no.
- 你是轱店工作的？
- 不，不。
I specialize in a very specific
type of security.
我的ｉL是一N非常
特殊型的安全――
Subconscious security.
意R安全。
You're talking about dreams?
你是在f糁幔
Are you talking about, um, extraction?
你是在f…唔…“提取”？
I am here to protect you.
我磉@Y是榱吮Ｗo你。
Mr. Fischer, I'm here
to protect you in the event...
M希先生，我磉@Y
是榱吮Ｗo你，以防…
...that someone tries to access
your mind through your dreams.
…有什N人企D通^
你的斫咏你的^X。
You're not safe here.
你在@Y不安全，
They're coming for you.
他碚夷懔恕
Strange weather, isn't it?
奇怪的天猓不是幔
You feel that?
感X到]有？
What's happening?
l生什N事了？
Cobb's drawing Fischer's attention
to the strangeness of the dream...
考博在引起M希
注意糁械钠娈F象，
...which is making his subconscious
look for the dreamer.
@使他的意R去ふ抑粽撸
For me. Quick, give me a kiss.
就是找我。快，o我吻。
- They're still looking at us.
- Yeah, it was worth a shot.
- 他在盯著我看啊。
- 是的，不^一下是值得的。
We should probably get out of here.
我最好是x_@Y。
You feel that? You've actually
been trained for this, Mr. Fischer.
你感X到那了幔磕H上
接受^@拥挠，M希先生。
Pay attention to the strangeness
of the weather, the shift in gravity.
注意天夤之的F象，
有重力的偏移。
None of this is real.
You're in a dream.
@一切都不是真的，
你是在粞Y。
Now, the easiest way
for you to test yourself...
你看最蔚霓k法
z你自己…
...is to try and remember how you
arrived at this hotel. Can you do that?
…就是回一下，你是如何淼
@家店的。你能起幔
Yeah, I...
唔，我不得了，我……
No, breathe, breathe.
Remember your training.
呼吸，做深呼吸。
回你受^的，
Accept the fact that you're in a dream,
and I'm here to protect you. Go on.
接受你F在在糁械氖，
我是磉@Y保o你的。加油。
Mm-hm.
嗯哼。
- You're not real?
- No. No.
- 你不是真的？
- ΓΑ
I'm a projection of your subconscious.
我是你的意R投影出淼摹
I was sent here to protect you
in the event...
我磉@Y是榱吮Ｗo你，以防…
...that extractors
tried to pull you into a dream.
…提取者想把你拖入下一簟
And I believe that's what's
going on right now, Mr. Fischer.
我相信@正是目前
正在l生的事情，M希先生。
Yeah.
是啊。
Okay.
好吧。
Can you get me out of here?
你能臀译x_@Y幔
Right away. Follow me.
F在就走，跟我怼
Hold on a second.
等一下。
Jesus Christ! What are you doing?
天哪！你在致铮
These men were sent here
to abduct you, all right?
@些人是被派斫架你的，明白幔
If you want my help,
you have to remain calm.
如果你想要我湍悖
你必保持o。
I need you to work with me, Mr. Fischer.
我需要你和我合作，M希先生。
If this is a dream, I should just
kill myself to wake up, right?
@是一簦
我只要⒘宋易约壕托砹耍幔
I wouldn't do that if I were you,
Mr. Fischer.
我要是你我不那N做，M希先生。
I believe they have you sedated,
and if you pull that trigger...
我相信他o你用了o，
如果…如果你扣幽扳C，
...you may not wake up.
你不醒恚
You may go into a further dream state.
Now, you know what I'm talking about.
你也SM入某N更深拥B。
你明白我在f什N。
You remember the training.
得你的幔
Remember what I said to you.
得我怎N教你的幔
Give me the gun.
把o我。
- This room should be directly below 528?
- Yeah.
- @房g直接在528下面？
- 是的。
Think, Mr. Fischer, think.
想想，M希先生，好好想想，
What do you remember
from before this dream?
@糁前你得什N？
There was, um, a lot of gunfire.
好像有…唔…好像有很激烈的穑
There was rain.
有…雨。
Uncle Peter.
彼得大叔。
- Oh, my God, we've been kidnapped.
- Where were they holding you?
- 噢我的上帝，我被架了。
- 他把你P在哪里？
- They had us in the back of a van.
- That explains the gravity shifts.
- 他我坐在一vI包的後面。
- @就解了槭颤N重力偏移。
You're in the back of a van.
Keep going.
你F在正坐在一vI包的後面。
^…^m！
It had something to do with, um...
有和…唔…
Something to do with a safe.
有和一保U有P。
God, why is it so hard to remember?
天哪，槭颤N那Ny回？
It's like trying to remember a dream
after you've woken up.
@就像是你醒磲
想要回你的粢樱
Listen, it takes years of practice.
你著，@需要有L年的`。
You and Browning have been pulled
into this dream...
你和白朗被入了@簦
...because they're trying to steal
something from your mind.
因樗想哪愕念^XY
I取什N|西。
I need you to focus and try
and remember what that is.
我需要你集中注意力，
回一下那是什N|西。
What is it, Mr. Fischer? Think!
是什N|西，M希先生？想想！
A combination. They demanded
the first numbers to pop into my head.
呃…一密a。他要求我蟪
我^XY冒出淼念^六底帧
They're trying to extract a number
from your subconscious.
他那是想哪愕意RY提取底帧
It can represent anything.
We're in a hotel right now.
它可以代表任何|西。
我F在是在一家店Y，
We should try hotel rooms.
What was the number, Mr. Fischer?
我一下店的房。
那底质鞘颤N，M希先生？
Try and remember for me.
This is very important.
快o我想想，因檫@非常重要。
Five.
5…
Five, two... It was something,
it was a long number.
5…2…是…
是更L一c的底帧…
That's good. We can start there.
Fifth floor.
可以了，我可以倪@_始。
五恰
Yep.
Α
- So do you use a timer?
- No, I have to judge it for myself.
- 那N你用r器幔
- 不用，我必自己做出判唷
While you're all asleep in 528,
I wait for Yusuf's kick.
你所有人都⑺在528房g，
我等待尤素福的反_。
- Well, how will you know?
- His music warns me.
- 你怎N知道呢？
- 他用音诽嵝盐摇
And then when the van
hits the barrier of the bridge,
接著就是I包撞上大虻淖o冢
that should be unmistakable.
那不搞e的。
So we get a nice synchronized kick.
於是我巧妙地使反_同步。
If it's too soon,
we won't get pulled out.
如果我行犹早，
那我⑸不去上樱
But if it's too late,
I won't be able to drop us.
但如果我行犹t，
那我就]k法@塌下怼
- Well, why not?
- Because the van will be in freefall.
- 槭颤N塌不下恚
- 因辄I包成樽杂陕潴w。
- Can't drop you without gravity.
- Right.
- ]有重力，就塌不下怼
- 是啊。
They're with me. Go on.
他是我的人。接著走。
Mr. Charles.
查理斯先生，
- Do you know what that is, Mr. Fischer?
- Yeah, I think so.
- 你知道@是致镉玫幔M希先生？
- 知道，我…我想我知道。
They were trying to put you under.
他想你到下面去。
- I'm already under.
- Under again.
- 我已在下面了。
- 再下一印
What do you mean,
a dream within a dream?
你什N意思？簟糁兄簦
Hey. I see you've changed.
嘿，我知道你又了。
I'm sorry?
Σ黄穑
Oh, I'm sorry.
I mistook you for a friend.
噢…抱歉，我`J槭俏遗笥蚜恕
Oh.
噢。
Good-looking fellow, I'm sure.
我想他一定很。
No, no, no. That's Fischer's
projection of Browning.
不，不，不。那是M希
意R投影的白朗。
Let's follow him and see how he behaves.
我跟著他砜纯此的行椤
- Why?
- Because how he acts will tell us...
- 槭颤N？
- 因樗的行告V我，
...if Fischer is starting to suspect
his motives the way we want him to.
是否M希已_始岩伤的C，
就像我希望的那印
Shh.
u……
- Uncle Peter.
- You said you were kidnapped together?
- 彼得大叔？
- 你f你一起被架的？
Well, not exactly. They already
had him. They were torturing him.
呃，唔…唔…不完全是。他…
他先抓的他，他一直在折磨他。
And you saw them torture him?
你看到他折磨他啦？
The kidnappers are working for you?
架者是槟值模
Robert.
_伯特……
You're trying to get that safe open?
To get the alternate will?
你想要打_那保U？
拿到另一份z冢
Fischer Morrow has been my entire life.
I can't let you destroy it.
“M希-莫_”是我的整生命，
我不能它г谀闶盅Y。
I'm not gonna throw away
my inheritance.
我不У粑业倪za！
槭颤N我那N做？
I couldn't let you rise
to your father's last taunt.
我]k法你反
你父H最後的鹤
- What taunt?
- The will, Robert. That will?
- 什N鹤。
- z冢_伯特，那份z冢
That's his last insult.
就是他最後的侮辱，
A challenge for you to build something
for yourself...
刺激你…你去建立你自己的事I，
...by telling you you're not worthy
of his accomplishments.
他告V你，你不配坐享其成
碛兴的成就。
- What, but that he was, um, disappointed?
- I'm sorry.
- 是啊，他是…唔…是很失望。
- 嗯，我很抱歉。
But he's wrong.
但是…他e了。
You can build a better company
than he ever did.
你能蚪立更好的企I，
比他做得好。
Mr. Fischer? He's lying.
M希先生？他在撒e。
- How do you know?
- Trust me, it's what I do.
- 你怎N知道？
- 相信我，我是诌@的。
He's hiding something,
and we need to find out what that is.
他在[m什N|西，
我必查明那到底是什N。
I need you to do the same thing to him
that he was going to do to you.
我需要你λ做同拥氖虑椋
而那本硎撬δ阕龅模
We'll enter his subconscious
我M入他的意R，
and find out what
he doesn't want you to know.
找出他不想你知道的|西。
All right.
好吧。
- He's out.
- Wait.
- 他著了。
- 等等，
Whose subconscious are
we going into exactly?
@一次我要M入哪一位的意R？
We're going into Fischer's.
我要M入M希的。
I told him it was Browning's
so he'd be a part of our team.
我_他f那是白朗的，
@铀就可以成槲中的一T。
He's gonna help us break
into his own subconscious.
他椭我突破
他自己的意R。
That's right.
]e。
Security's gonna run you down hard.
他的l追得你FFD的。
And I will lead them on a merry chase.
那我就好好地涮他一遭。
- Just be back before the kick.
- Go to sleep, Mr. Eames.
- 但@Y反_前能上怼
- 睡你的吧，伊姆斯先生。
You good?
你]事吧？
Hey. You ready?
嘿，你浜昧幔
Yes, yes. I'm fine. I'm ready.
是的，我…我很好，我浜昧恕
Cobb?
考博？
Cobb? What's down there?
考博？那Y有什N？
Hopefully, the truth
we want Fischer to learn.
希望是我想M希W到的真相。
I mean, what's down there for you?
我是f那Yδ碚f有什N？
Did you see that?
哈，你看到]？
Eames, this is your dream.
伊姆斯，@是你的簦
I need you to draw the security away
from the complex, understand?
我需要你把l慕êB群
那阂_，你明白幔
- Who guides Fischer in?
- Not me.
- 那lьIM希M去？
- 我不行。
If I know the route,
everything could be compromised.
如果我知道了路剑
一切都可能遭到危害。
- I designed the place.
- No, you're with me.
- 我O的@地方。
- 不，你和我呆在一起。
I could do it.
我可以和他一起M去。
All right. Brief him on the route
into the complex.
好的。你向他谓榻B下
M入建B群的路健
- Fischer, you'll be going with him.
- All right. What about you?
- M希，你和他一起去。
- 好的。你质颤N？
You keep this live.
I'll be listening in the whole time.
一直_著@，我rrO的。
The windows on that upper floor...
上拥哪切┐糇虼螅
...are big enough for me to cover you
from that south tower. You see it?
我可以哪线那塔
掩o你。看到了幔
You're not coming in?
看到了。你不M去幔
In order to find out the truth
about your father...
榱苏页鲫P於你父H的真相，
...you're gonna need to break into
Browning's mind on your own.
你必自己J入白朗的^X。
Come on, Fischer!
我走，M希！
- Sound the alarm! Sound the alarm!
- Go, go, go!
- 快拉警螅】炖警螅
- 快，快，快！
Move!
快走！
Go!
走！
Sod it.
操！
I hope you're ready.
希望你浜昧恕
No, it's too soon.
不，@也太早了吧。
Cobb, do you hear that?
考博，你了幔
I first noticed it about 20 minutes ago,
我第一次注意是20分以前，
I thought it was the wind up here.
我以槭沁@上面的L呢。
Yeah, I hear it. It's music.
是的，我了，是音贰
So, what do we do?
那N我怎Nk？
We move fast.
我抓o行樱
Yusuf's 10 seconds from the jump.
尤素福10秒後起跳，
Which gives Arthur three minutes.
那o瑟3分rg，
- Hey!
- That's him!
- 嘿！
- 就是他！
- Which gives us what?
- Sixty minutes.
- 那No我呢？
- 60分。
- Can they make that route in an hour?
- They have to climb to the terrace.
- 他能蛟谝恍r哪l路竭M入幔
- 他得往下爬到中悠脚_。
Then they need a new route,
a more direct route.
那N他需要一l新路剑
一l更直接的路健
It's designed as a labyrinth.
它是按迷m碓O的。
There must be access routes
that cut through the maze.
但一定存在通向迷m捷降耐ǖ溃幔
Eames?
伊姆斯？
Did Eames add any features?
伊姆斯有]有附加其他的Y？
I don't think I should tell you.
我想我不告V你。
要是lF了……
We don't have time for this.
Did he add anything?
我]rg@。
他有]有加什N|西？
He added an air-duct system
that can cut through the maze.
他加了通L管道系y，
那可以成槊m的捷健
Good. Explain it to them.
很好，o他f明一下。
- Saito?
- Go ahead.
- S藤？
- f。
Paradox.
悖。
- What was that?
- The kick.
- 那是什N？
- 反_。
Cobb! Cobb, did we miss it?
考博！考博，我e^了幔
Yeah, we missed it.
是的，我e^了。
Man.
嘿！
Couldn't someone have dreamt up
a goddamn beach? Huh?
他的怎N不做海┑簦抗？
Uh-huh.
啊哈。
Well, what the hell do we do now?
那我F在他的怎Nk？
We finish the job before the next kick.
在下一反_之前完成任铡
- What next kick?
- When the van hits the water.
- 什N下一反_？
- I包糁兴面的r候。
If you'd like to make a call,
please hang up and try again.
如果您想打，
C然後再芤淮巍
If you need help, hang up...
如果你需要椭，C……
How do I drop you without gravity?
]有重力我怎N你掉下去？
Arthur has a couple minutes,
and we have about 20.
瑟有煞昼rg，
我有大s20分。
You okay?
你好幔
Run! Turn around!
Move to base! Move to base!
快！快D回去！
回大本I去！回大本I！
Go, go, go!
快，快，快！
There's something wrong.
有什N不牛
They're heading your way,
like they know something.
他都往你那夯爻妨耍
好像他知道了什N。
Just buy us more time, all right?
再拖延crg，行幔
- Come on!
- On my way.
- 我走！
- 我砹恕
Come on! Move!
快c！快啊！
All right.
好了。
Okay. That's the antechamber
outside the strong room.
好了。那是保U焱饷娴慕哟d。
- Does the strong room have windows?
- It wouldn't be very strong if it did.
- 那保U煊]有窗裟兀
- 有窗舻脑就不保U了。
Let's hope Fischer likes
what he finds in there.
希望M希喜g
他在那喊lF的|西。
- Are those projections his subconscious?
- Yes.
- 那些投影是他意R的一部分幔
- 是的。
- Are you destroying parts of his mind?
- No. They're just projections.
- 那你不У羲^X的那些部分？
- 不，不，他只是投影而已。
- We're here.
- You're clear, but hurry.
- 我到了。
- Y面]情r，但幼饕快。
There's an entire army headed your way.
全部人R都在向你怼
I'm in.
我M砹恕
There he is.
他在那骸
- There's someone in there.
- Fischer, it's a trap. Get out.
- 有人在Y面。
- M希，那是陷阱。快x_！
Come on. Come on, a little lower.
快c，快c，再低一c。
Cobb.
考博，
No, she is not real.
不，她…她不是真的。
How do you know that?
你怎N知道的？
She is just a projection.
Fischer. Fischer is real.
她只是一投影。
M希…M希才是真的。
Hello.
你好。
Eames! Eames, get to the antechamber now!
伊姆斯！伊姆斯！快到接待d去！
- What happened?
- Mal killed Fischer.
- 出什N事了？
- ⒘M希。
I couldn't shoot her.
我早c_。
There's no use in reviving him.
His mind's already trapped down there.
救他已]意x了，即使救^恚
他的^X已陷落到下面去了。
It's all over.
一切都Y束了。
So that's it, then? We failed?
就@油炅耍课失×耍
We're done. I'm sorry.
我完了，我很抱歉。
It's not me that doesn't get back
to my family, is it?
我o所^，又不是我
不能c家人F聚，不是N？
It's a shame. I really wanted to know
what was gonna happen in there.
太可惜了，我真的很想知道
那Y面l生什N，
I swear we had this one.
我好不容易到了@一步。
Let's set the charges.
我b炸吧。
No, there's still another way.
不，有一k法。
- We have to follow Fischer down there.
- Not enough time.
- 我只要跟著M希下去。
- rg不蛄恕
No, but there will be
enough time down there.
不，那Y…那下面有足虻rg。
And we will find him, okay?
我找到他，幔
As soon as Arthur's music kicks in,
一旦瑟的音吩谶@喉起，
just use the defibrillator to revive him.
你就用羝魇顾恢托奶，
We can give him his own kick
down below.
我在下面也…也o他一反_。
Look, you get him in there.
你看，然後你他到那Y面去。
As soon as the music ends,
you blow up the hospital...
一旦音吠Ｖ梗你就炸н@所t院，
...and we all ride the kick
back up the layers.
我所有人都乘著反_
一踊氐缴厦嫒ァ
It's worth a shot, if Saito can hold
the guards off while I set the charges.
很值得一，如果S藤可以
守o@Y，我去把炸b好。
Saito will never make it, will he?
S藤已快不行了。
- Cobb, come on. We've gotta try this.
- Go for it.
- 考博，快c，我一下。
- 行影伞
If you are not back before the kick,
I am gone with or without you.
如果@Y反_的r候你]回恚
那我就自己上去了。
She's right. She's right.
Come on. Let's go.
她f得Γ她f得Α
走，我走。
Can I trust you to do
what needs to happen here?
我能信任你幔
不重蹈@旱母厕H？
Mal's gonna be down there.
我是f在那下I。
I know where to find her.
She'll have Fischer.
我知道哪里能找到她，
她еM希。
- How do you know?
- Because she wants me to come after him.
- 你怎N知道？
- 因樗想我去追他，
She wants me back down there with her.
她想我回到那下面跟她在一起。
All right?
你好幔
- This is your world?
- It was.
- @是你的世界？
- 曾是。
And this is where she'll be.
她就在@Y。
Come on.
走吧。
Saito. Saito.
S藤，S藤！
I need you to take care of Fischer
while I go set some charges, okay?
我需要你，我需要你看著cM希，
我要去安b炸，明白幔
No room for tourists on these jobs.
@拥幕河^光客可]有位置。
Don't be silly.
e傻了。
You built all this?
This is incredible.
@些都是你建造的？
太不可思h了。
We built for years.
我建造了很多年。
Then we started in on the memories.
我{_始建造。
This way.
@走。
This was our neighborhood.
@Y是我的街坊，
Places from our past.
我那白∵^的地方。
That was our first apartment.
那是我的第一套公寓，
Then we moved to that building right there.
後碛职岬搅四沁的那大茄Y。
After Mal became pregnant,
that became our home.
在言幸葬幔
那撼闪宋的家。
You reconstructed all of this from memory?
你{就重建了所有@一切？
Like I told you, we had lots of time.
就像我跟你f^，我有很多的rg。
What is that?
那是什N？
That's the house Mal grew up in.
在那房子YL大。
- Well, will she be in there?
- No.
- 她在Y面幔
- 不。
Come on.
快c。
We both wanted to live in a house,
but we loved this type of building.
我z都想住在平宅房Y，
但我也喜g@N型的大恰
In the real world, we'd have
to choose, but not here.
在真世界Y，我不得不x瘢
但在@Y不必。
How are we gonna bring Fischer back?
我怎N把M希Щ厝ィ
We're gonna have to come up
with some kind of a kick.
我得想出某N反_的k法。
What?
怎N做？
I'm gonna improvise.
我得SC。
Listen, there's something you should
know about me. About inception.
著，P於我有些事情
你t解，P於“l”。
An idea is like a virus.
意念就像是病毒，
Resilient. Highly contagious.
非常有g拧O具魅拘浴
And the smallest seed of an idea can grow.
意念的一最最微小的N子能虺砷L，
It can grow to define...
它L大後能蛩茉炷恪
...or destroy you.
…或缒恪
The smallest idea, such as:
最微小的意念，例如：
"Your world is not real."
“你的世界不是真的。”
Simple little thought
that changes everything.
@雍蔚男∠敕可以改一切。
So certain of your world.
Of what's real.
那N_信你的世界，
_信什N是真的？
Do you think he is?
你J樗真幔
Or do you think he's as lost as I was?
你不J樗也可能像我那耙用允В
I know what's real, Mal.
我知道什N是真的，。
No creeping doubts?
]有可怕的岩桑
Not feeling persecuted, Dom?
]有感到^困_，多姆？
Chased around the globe by anonymous
corporations and police forces...
被o名公司和T警CP
追得M世界y跑？
...the way the projections
persecute the dreamer?
那些投影困_做粽叩姆绞剑
Admit it.
承J吧，
You don't believe in one reality anymore.
你不再相信只有一F。
So choose.
所以x癜桑
Choose to be here.
x窳粼谶@Y，
Choose me.
x裎摇
You know what I have to do.
你知道我必做什N，
I have to get back to our children
because you left them.
我必回到我的孩子身，
因槭悄汶x_了他，
Because you left us.
因槭悄汶x_了我。
- You're wrong.
- I'm not wrong.
- 你e了！
- 我]e。
You're confused.
你糊T了。
Our children are here.
我的孩子都在@Y。
And you'd like to see
their faces again, wouldn't you?
你很想再一次看他的面孔，是不是？
Yes, but I'm gonna see them up above, Mal.
是的，但是我想要到上面看他，。
Up above?
上面？
Listen to yourself.
These are our children.
你自己f的，
@些就是我的孩子。
Watch.
你看。
James? Phillipa?
詹姆士？菲利帕？
Don't do this, Mal. Please.
Those aren't my children.
e@樱，求你了。
那些不是我的孩子。
You keep telling yourself that,
but you don't believe it.
你一直@δ阕约赫f，
但是你自己都不相信。
- No, I know it.
- What if you're wrong?
- 不，我知道的！
- 要是你e了呢？
What if I'm what's real?
要是我是真的呢？
You keep telling yourself what you know.
你一直告V你自己你是知道的，
But what do you believe?
但是你相信什N？
What do you feel?
你的感X是什N？
Guilt.
染危
I feel guilt, Mal.
我感到染危。
And no matter what I do,
no matter how hopeless I am...
不管我做什N，不管…
不管我怎咏^望，
...no matter how confused,
that guilt is always there...
不管我怎永Щ螅
那N染慰是在那Y，
...reminding me of the truth.
提醒我那真相。
What truth?
什N真相？
That the idea that caused you to
question your reality came from me.
就是那е履阗|疑
你的F的意念碜造段摇
You planted the idea in my mind?
是你把那意念植入我^XY的？
What is she talking about?
她在f什N？
The reason I knew inception was possible...
我知道“l”是可行的原因…
...was because I did it to her first.
…是因槲摇我λ先做^，
- I did it to my own wife.
- Why?
- 我ξ易约旱钠拮幼鲞^。
- 槭颤N？
We were lost in here.
我迷失在了@Y，
I knew we needed to escape,
but she wouldn't accept it.
我知道我必逃x，
但是她不意接受。
She had locked something away,
something deep inside.
她把什N|西i了起恚
深深地i在了她的^XY。
A truth that she had once known,
but chose to forget.
她曾知道真相，
但是她x窳诉z忘。
And she couldn't break free.
她o法逃。
So I decided to search for it.
於是我Q定去搜索，
I went deep into the recess of her mind
and found that secret place.
我M入了她^X最[秘的深，
找到了那秘密的地方。
And I broke in...
我J了M去，
...and I planted an idea.
然後我植入了一意念，
A simple little idea
that would change everything.
一蔚男⌒〉囊饽
改一切。
That her world wasn't real.
那就是她的世界不是真的，
That death was the only escape.
死亡是唯一的出路。
You're waiting for a train.
你在等一列火，
A train that'll take you far away.
一列你去向h方的火。
You know where you hope
this train will take you...
你知道你希望@列火
你去向何方，
...but you can't know for sure.
但是你不能_定，
Yet it doesn't matter.
不^那也]PS。
- Now, tell me why!
- Because you'll be together!
- 告V我槭颤N！
- 因槟在一起！
But I never knew that that idea
would grow in her mind like a cancer...
但是我]料到的是，那意念
在她^XY像癌一映砷L，
...that even after she woke...
即使在她醒硪葬幔
That even after you came back to reality...
即使在你回到F之後，
...that you'd continue to believe
your world wasn't real.
你^m相信你的世界不是真的，
That death was the only escape.
死亡是唯一的出路。
Mal, no! Jesus!
！不！耶d……
- You infected my mind.
- I was trying to save you.
- 你感染了我的^X？
- 我只是想挽救你。
You betrayed me.
你背叛了我。
But you can make amends.
You can still keep your promise.
但是你仍然能a，
你仍然能蛐攀啬愕闹Z言。
We can still be together, right here...
我仍然可以在一起，就在@Y，
...in the world we built together.
在@我一起建造的世界Y。
Cobb, we need to get Fischer.
考博，我必找到M希。
You can't have him.
我不交o你的。
- If I stay here, will you let him go?
- What are you talking about?
- 如果我留在@Y，你放他走幔
- 你在f什N？
Fischer is on the porch.
M希在_上。
- Go check he's alive, Ariadne.
- Cobb, you can't do this.
- 看看他是否活^砹耍阿Y阿德涅。
- 考博，你不能@N做。
Go check he's alive right now. Do it.
去z查一下他是否活^砹耍快，快去。
He's here! And it's time,
but you have to come now!
他醒^砹耍〉rg了，
你必立刻^恚
- You take Fischer with you, all right?
- You can't stay here to be with her.
- 你上M希so走，行幔
- 你不能留在@汉退在一起。
I'm not. Saito's dead by now.
我不。S藤F在已死了，
That means he's down here somewhere.
That means I have to find him.
就是f他也在@Y的某地方，
也就是f我必得找到他。
I can't stay with her anymore,
because she doesn't exist.
我不再留在@Y陪著她了，
因樗K不存在。
I'm the only thing you do believe in anymore.
我是你以後唯一能蛳嘈诺娜恕
No.
不。
I wish.
我希望…
I wish more than anything, but...
我^Φ叵Ｍ，但是…
...I can't imagine you
with all your complexity...
我o法想像你的那些}s的性情，
...all your perfection,
all your imperfection.
你所有的完美、
你所有的不完美。
- You all right?
- Yeah.
- 你好幔
- 好。
Look at you.
看看你自己，
You're just a shade.
You're just a shade of my real wife.
你只是影，
你只是我真正妻子的影。
And you were the best
that I could do, but...
δ阄乙呀M力了，但是…
...I'm sorry, you're just not good enough.
Σ黄穑你只是不蚝谩
Does this feel real?
@感X真不真？
- What are you doing?
- Improvising.
- 你在致铮
- SC。
No, no, no!
不，不，不！
In there, now. Go, go, go.
在那Y面，快去！快，快，快！
I was dis...
我很失…
I was dis... Disa...
我很失…失……
- I know, Dad.
- ...dis...
- 我知道，爸爸。
- 失……
I know you were disappointed...
我知道你很失望，
...I couldn't be you.
我]能成槟恪
No.
不。
No, no, no.
不，不，不。
I was disappointed...
我失望的是…
...that you tried.
…你只想成槲摇
What?
什N？
Come on, come on.
快c，快c。
（“最Kz凇保
Dad?
爸爸？
That's the kick, Ariadne!
You have to go now!
那是反_，阿Y阿德涅！
你必立刻就走！
Don't lose yourself!
Find Saito and bring him back!
小心e迷失自己！
找到S藤把他Щ恚
I will!
我的！
You remember when you asked me
to marry you?
得你向我求婚的念^
是怎N淼幔
Yes.
得。
You said you dreamt
that we'd grow old together.
你f你舻搅宋一起老。
But we did.
我已做了。
We did. You don't remember?
我做了，你不得了幔
I miss you more than I can bear...
我o法忍受δ愕乃寄睿但是…
...but we had our time together.
…我有^我共度的r光。
And I have to let you go.
我不得不放你走，
I have to let you go.
我不得不放你走。
I'm sorry, Robert.
Σ黄穑_伯特。
You know, the will means that Dad
wanted me to be my own man...
你知道，那z诘囊馑际
爸爸想我成槲易约海
...not just to live for him.
而不只是樗而活著。
That's what I'm gonna do, Uncle Peter.
@也正是我打算要做的，彼得大叔。
What happened?
出什N事了？
- Cobb stayed.
- With Mal?
- 考博留在了那Y。
- 和在一起？
No, to find Saito.
不，去找S藤。
He'll be lost.
他迷失的。
No, he'll be all right.
不，他]事的。
Have you come to kill me?
你是⑽业幔
I'm waiting for someone.
我一直在等一人，
Someone from a half-remembered dream.
一依稀得的粞Y的人。
Cobb?
考博？
Impossible.
怎N可能？
We were young men together.
我在一起r那N年p，
I'm an old man.
我F在成了老人。
Filled with regret.
心中充Mz憾？
Waiting to die alone.
在孤中等待死亡，嗯？
I've come back for you.
我是回碚夷愕模
To remind you of something.
硖嵝涯阋患事情…
Something you once knew.
一件你曾知道的事情：
That this world is not real.
@世界不是真的。
To convince me to honor our arrangement?
碚f服我履行我的fh？
To take a leap of faith, yes.
硪信心上的wS，是的。
Come back...
回去…
...so we can be young men together again.
我就可以得年p，再一次在一起。
Come back with me.
和我一起回去。
Come back.
回去。
Hot towel, sir?
需要崦巾N，先生？
We'll be landing in Los Angeles
in about 20 minutes.
我⒃诖蠹s二十分後
在洛杉降落。
Do you need immigration forms?
你需要入境登表N？
Thank you.
xx。
Hot towel, sir?
需要崦巾N，先生？
- No.
- Do you need immigration forms?
- 噢，不用。
- 需要入境登表N？
Welcome home, Mr. Cobb.
g迎回家，考博先生。
Thank you, sir.
xx。
（“M希”）
Welcome.
g迎。
This way.
@走。
James? Phillipa?
詹姆士？菲利帕？
Look who's here.
看看l砹恕
Hey.
嘿。
- Hey, guys! Hey! How are you?
- Daddy! Daddy!
- 嘿，孩子！嘿！你好幔
- 爹地！爹地！
Daddy! How are you?
爹地！你好幔
Look what I've been building!
看看我造了什N？
- What are you building?
- We're building a house on the cliff!
- 你在造什N？
- 我在已律显炝艘蛔房子！
On the cliff? Come on, I want you
to show me. Can you show me?
在已律希靠禳c，快我看看。
我看看好幔
Let's go. Come on, Daddy!
我走。快c，爹地！
《l》
[ translation & synchronization: 639 ]
[ 翻g 同步：639 ]
[ thanks for watching! ]
[ xx^p！]